<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<root>
  <q id="1">
    <d>(on love) It&apos;s the only thing which allows men and women to stand in a world where gravity always seems to want to pull them down... bring them low... and make them crawl.</d>
    <a>Stephen King</a>
  </q>
  <q id="2">
    <d>A baby is born with a need to be loved - and never outgrows it.</d>
    <a>Frank A. Clark</a>
  </q>
  <q id="3">
    <d>A coward is incapable of exhibiting love; it is the prerogative of the brave.</d>
    <a>Mahatma Gandhi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="4">
    <d>A good marriage winds up as a meeting of minds, which had better be pretty good to start with.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="5">
    <d>A heart that loves is always young.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="6">
    <d>A kiss is a lovely trick designed by nature to stop speech when words become superfluous.</d>
    <a>Ingrid Bergman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="7">
    <d>A life without love in it is like a heap of ashes upon a deserted hearth, with the fire dead, the laughter stilled and the light extinguished.</d>
    <a>Frank Tebbets</a>
  </q>
  <q id="8">
    <d>A love affair with knowledge will never end in heartbreak.</d>
    <a>Michael Garrett Marino</a>
  </q>
  <q id="9">
    <d>A lover without indiscretion is no lover at all. Circumspection and devotion are a contradiction in terms.</d>
    <a>Thomas Hardy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="10">
    <d>A lover, when he is admitted to cards, ought to be solemnly silent, and observe the motions of his mistress. He must laugh when she laughs, sigh when she sighs. In short, he should be the shadow of her mind. A lady, in the presence of her lover, should never want a looking-glass; as a beau, in the presence of his looking-glass, never wants a mistress.</d>
    <a>Henry Fielding</a>
  </q>
  <q id="11">
    <d>A loving heart is the truest wisdom.</d>
    <a>Charles Dickens</a>
  </q>
  <q id="12">
    <d>A man can go from being a lover to being a stranger in three moves flat but a woman under the guise of friendship will engage in acts of duplicity which come to light very much later. There are different species of self-justification.</d>
    <a>Anita Brookner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="13">
    <d>A man falls in love through his eyes, a woman through her ears.</d>
    <a>Woodrow Wyatt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="14">
    <d>A man has only one escape from his old self: to see a different self in the mirror of some woman&apos;s eyes.</d>
    <a>Clare Boothe Luce</a>
  </q>
  <q id="15">
    <d>A man in love is like a clipped coupon - it&apos;s time to cash in.</d>
    <a>Mae West</a>
  </q>
  <q id="16">
    <d>A man in love mistakes a pimple for a dimple.</d>
    <a>Japanese Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="17">
    <d>A man reserves his true and deepest love not for the species of woman in whose company he finds himself electrified and enkindled, but for that one in whose company he may feel tenderly drowsy.</d>
    <a>George Jean Nathan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="18">
    <d>A man travels the world over in search of what he needs and returns home to find it.</d>
    <a>George Moore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="19">
    <d>A mighty pain to love it is, and &apos;tis a pain that pain to miss; but of all the pains, the greatest pain is to love, but love in vain.</d>
    <a>Abraham Crowley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="20">
    <d>A pity beyond all telling is hid in the heart of love.</d>
    <a>William Butler Yeats</a>
  </q>
  <q id="21">
    <d>A proof that experience is of no use, is that the end of one love does not prevent us from beginning another.</d>
    <a>Paul Bourget</a>
  </q>
  <q id="22">
    <d>A relationship is like a rose,How long it lasts, no one knows;Love can erase an awful past,Love can be yours, you&apos;ll see at last;To feel that love, it makes you sigh,To have it leave, you&apos;d rather die;You hope you&apos;ve found that special rose,&apos;Cause you love and care for the one you chose.</d>
    <a>Rob Cella</a>
  </q>
  <q id="23">
    <d>A slight touch of friendly malice and amusement towards those we love keeps our affections for them from turning flat.</d>
    <a>Logan Pearsall Smith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="24">
    <d>A supreme love, a motive that gives a sublime rhythm to a woman&apos;s life, and exalts habit into partnership with the soul&apos;s highest needs, is not to be had where and how she wills.</d>
    <a>George Eliot</a>
  </q>
  <q id="25">
    <d>A very small degree of hope is sufficient to cause the birth of love.</d>
    <a> Stendhal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="26">
    <d>A very small degree of hope is sufficient to cause the birth of love.</d>
    <a>Stendhal (Marie-Henri Beyle)</a>
  </q>
  <q id="27">
    <d>A woman has got to love a bad man once or twice in her life to be thankful for a good one.</d>
    <a>Mae West</a>
  </q>
  <q id="28">
    <d>A woman who could always love would never grow old; and the love of mother and wife would often give or preserve many charms if it were not too often combined with parental and conjugal anger. There remains in the face of women who are naturally serene and peaceful, and of those rendered so by religion, an after-spring, and later an after-summer, the reflex of their most beautiful bloom.</d>
    <a>Jean Paul Richter</a>
  </q>
  <q id="29">
    <d>A woman&apos;s life is a history of the affections.</d>
    <a>Washington Irving</a>
  </q>
  <q id="30">
    <d>Absence diminishes small loves and increases great ones, as the wind blows out the candle and blows up the bonfire.</d>
    <a>La Rochefoucauld</a>
  </q>
  <q id="31">
    <d>Absence is to love what wind is to fire; it extinguishes the small, it enkindles the great.</d>
    <a>Comte DeBussy-Rabutin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="32">
    <d>Accept the things to which fate binds you, and love the people with whom fate brings you together, but do so with all your heart.</d>
    <a>Marcus Aurelius</a>
  </q>
  <q id="33">
    <d>Affection, like melancholy, magnifies trifles; but the magnifying of the one is like looking through a telescope at heavenly objects; that of the other, like enlarging monsters with a microscope.</d>
    <a>Leigh Hunt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="34">
    <d>After all, what was more important, in the end, than love?</d>
    <a>Stephenie Meyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="35">
    <d>Ah, how skilful grows the hand That obeyeth Love&apos;s command! It is the heart, and not the brain, That to the highest doth attain, And he who followeth Love&apos;s behest Far excelleth all the rest!</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="36">
    <d>Ah, then, upon my bedroom I do draw The blind to hide the garden, where the moonEnjoys the open blossoms as they strawTheir beauty for his taking, boon for boon.And I do lift my aching arms to you,And I do lift my anguished, avid breast,And I do weep for very pain of you,And fling myself at the doors of sleep, for rest.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="37">
    <d>All is fair in love and war.</d>
    <a>Francis Edward Smedley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="38">
    <d>All love is sweet, Given or returned. Common as light is love, And its familiar voice wearies not ever. They who inspire is most are fortunate, As I am now: but those who feel it most Are happier still.</d>
    <a>Percy Bysshe Shelley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="39">
    <d>All love that has not friendship for its base, is like a mansion built upon the sand.</d>
    <a>Ella Wheeler Wilcox</a>
  </q>
  <q id="40">
    <d>All my life I have had a choice of hate and love. I chose love and I am here.</d>
    <a>A.R. Rahman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="41">
    <d>All the pictures that hung in my memory before I knew you have faded and given place to our radient moments together. Now I cannot live apart from you...Your words are my food, your breath my wine. You are everything to me.</d>
    <a>Sarah Bernhardt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="42">
    <d>All thoughts, all passions, all delightsWhatever stirs this mortal frameAll are but ministers of LoveAnd feed His sacred flame.</d>
    <a>Samuel Taylor Coleridge</a>
  </q>
  <q id="43">
    <d>All, everything that I understand, I understand only because I love.</d>
    <a>Leo Tolstoy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="44">
    <d>An act of love that fails is just as much a part of the divine life as an act of love that succeeds, for love is measured by fullness, not by reception.</d>
    <a>Harold Lokes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="45">
    <d>An affair wants to spill, to share its glory with the world. No act is so private it does not seek applause.</d>
    <a>John Updike</a>
  </q>
  <q id="46">
    <d>An orange on the table, your dress on the rug, and you in my bed, sweet present of the present, cool of night, warmth of my life.</d>
    <a>Jacques Prevert</a>
  </q>
  <q id="47">
    <d>An orange on the table, your dress on the rug, and you in my bed, sweet present of the present, cool of night, warmth of my life.</d>
    <a>Jacques Pr?vert</a>
  </q>
  <q id="48">
    <d>And this I pray, that your love may abound still more and more in real knowledge and all discernment. Philippians 1:9</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="49">
    <d>And when the future hinges on the next words that are said, don&apos;t let logic interfere, believe your heart instead.</d>
    <a>Philip Robison</a>
  </q>
  <q id="50">
    <d>And you are to love those who are your aliens for you yourselves were aliens in Egypt. Deuteronomy 10:19</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="51">
    <d>And, oh, how blessed is it thus to meet! To feel that vanished years have not estranged us,distance has not diminished love, that we are to each other even as we parted; to feel again the fond kiss, to hear once more the accents of a voice which to us has been for years so still,-a voice that brings with it the gush of memory! Past days flit before us; feelings, thoughts, hopes, we deemed were dead, all rise again, summoned by that secret witchery, the well-remembered though long silent voice. Let years, long, lingering, saddening years drag on their chain, let youth have given place to manhood, manhood to age, still will it be the same-the voice we once have loved, and deemed to us for ever still-oh, time, and grief, and blighted hope will be forgotten, and youth, in its undimmed and joyous beauty, its glow of generous feelings, its bright anticipations, all, all again be ours.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="52">
    <d>Another kind of love and compassion is not based on something appearing beautiful or nice, but based on the fact that the other person, just like oneself, wants happiness and does not want suffering and indeed has every right to be happy and to overcome suffering. On such a basis, we feel a sense of responsibility, a sense of closeness toward that being. That is true compassion. This is because the compassion is based on reason, notjust on emotional feeling. As a consequence, it does not matter what the other&apos;s attitude is, whether negative, or positive. What matters is that it is a human being, a sentient being that has the experience of pain and pleasure. There is no reason not to feel compassion so long as it is a sentient being.</d>
    <a>Dalai Lama</a>
  </q>
  <q id="53">
    <d>Any woman who thinks the way to a man&apos;s heart is through his stomach is aiming about 10 inches too high.</d>
    <a>Adrienne Gusoff</a>
  </q>
  <q id="54">
    <d>Anything will give up its secrets if you love it enough. Not only have I found that when I talk to the little flower or to the little peanut they will give up their secrets, but I have found that when I silently commune with people they give up their secrets also - if you love them enough.</d>
    <a>George Washington</a>
  </q>
  <q id="55">
    <d>Are you ready to cut off your head and place your foot on it? If so, come; Love awaits you! Love is not grown in a garden, nor sold in the marketplace; whether you are a king or a servant, the price is your head, and nothing less. Yes, the cost of the elixir of love is your head! Do you hesitate? 0 miser, It is cheap at that price!</d>
    <a>Abu Hamid Al-Ghazzali</a>
  </q>
  <q id="56">
    <d>Art is not necessary at all. All that is necessary to make this world a better place to live in is to love -to love as Christ loved, as Buddha loved.</d>
    <a>Isadora Duncan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="57">
    <d>As for me, to love you alone, to make you happy, to do nothing which would contradict your wishes, this is my destiny and the meaning of my life.</d>
    <a>Napoleon Bonaparte</a>
  </q>
  <q id="58">
    <d>As love without esteem is capricious and volatile; esteem without love is languid and cold.</d>
    <a>Jonathan Swift</a>
  </q>
  <q id="59">
    <d>As Plato sometimes speaks of the divine love, it arises not out of indigency, as created love does, but out of fullness and redundancy; it is an overflowing fountain, and that love which descends upon created being is a free efflux from the almighty source of love; and it is well pleasing to him that those creatures which he hath made should partake of it.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="60">
    <d>At any rate, let us love for a while, for a year or so, you and me. That&apos;s a form of divine drunkenness that we can all try.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="61">
    <d>At the beginning and at the end of love, the two lovers are embarrassed to find themselves alone.</d>
    <a>Jean De La Bruyere</a>
  </q>
  <q id="62">
    <d>At the center of non-violence stands the principle of love.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther King</a>
  </q>
  <q id="63">
    <d>At the center of non-violence stands the principle of love.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther King, Jr.</a>
  </q>
  <q id="64">
    <d>At the touch of love everyone becomes a poet.</d>
    <a>Plato</a>
  </q>
  <q id="65">
    <d>At the touch of love, everyone becomes a poet.</d>
    <a> Plato</a>
  </q>
  <q id="66">
    <d>Be glad of life because it gives you the chance to love and to work and to play and to look up at the stars.</d>
    <a>Henry Van Dyke</a>
  </q>
  <q id="67">
    <d>Before I met my husband, I&apos;d never fallen in love, though I&apos;d stepped in it a few times. </d>
    <a>Rita Rudner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="68">
    <d>
      Before I met my husband, I&apos;d never fallen in love. I&apos;d stepped in it
      a few times.
    </d>
    <a>Rita Rudner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="69">
    <d>Being always overavid, I demand from those I love a love equal to mine, which, being balanced people, they cannot supply.</d>
    <a>Sylvia Ashton-Warner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="70">
    <d>Being deeply loved by someone gives you strength, while loving someone deeply gives you courage.</d>
    <a>Lao Tzu</a>
  </q>
  <q id="71">
    <d>Being in love was like China: you knew it was there, and no doubt it was very interesting, and some people went there, but I never would. I&apos;d spend all my life without ever going to China, but it wouldn&apos;t matter, because there was all the rest of the world to visit.</d>
    <a>Phillip Pullman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="72">
    <d>Better never to have met you in my dream than to wake and reach for hands that are not there.</d>
    <a>Otomo No Yakamochi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="73">
    <d>Better to have loved a short man than never to have loved a tall.</d>
    <a>David Chambless</a>
  </q>
  <q id="74">
    <d>Better to have loved and lost, than to have never loved at all.</d>
    <a> St. Augustine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="75">
    <d>Between lovers a little confession is a dangerous thing.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="76">
    <d>Blue eyes say, Love me or I die; black eyes say, Love me or I kill thee.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="77">
    <d>Busy old fool, unruly Sun, why dost thou thus through windows and through curtains call on us? Must to thy motions lovers seasons run?</d>
    <a>John Donne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="78">
    <d>But I always think that the best way to know God is to love many things.</d>
    <a>Vincent Van Gogh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="79">
    <d>But it is impossible to replace a person one has loved with distractions.</d>
    <a>Roald Dahl</a>
  </q>
  <q id="80">
    <d>But love is blind, and lovers cannot see What petty follies they themselves commit</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="81">
    <d>But that intimacy of mutual embarrassment, in which each feels that the other is feeling something, having once existed, its effect is not to be done away with.</d>
    <a>George Eliot</a>
  </q>
  <q id="82">
    <d>But true love is a durable fire, in the mind ever burning. Never sick, never old, never dead. From itself never turning.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="83">
    <d>But when a young lady is to be a heroine, the perverseness of forty surrounding families cannot prevent her. Something must and will happen to throw a hero in her way. </d>
    <a>Jane Austen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="84">
    <d>By this all men will know that you are my disciples, if you have love for one another. John 13:35</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="85">
    <d>Can there be a love which does not make demands on its object?</d>
    <a>Confucius</a>
  </q>
  <q id="86">
    <d>Clarity of mind means clarity of passion, too; this is why a great and clear mind loves ardently and sees distinctly what it loves. </d>
    <a>Blaise Pascal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="87">
    <d>Come live in my heart, and pay no rent.</d>
    <a>Samuel Lover</a>
  </q>
  <q id="88">
    <d>Come live with me, and be my love,And we will some new pleasures proveOf golden sands, and crystal brooks,With silken lines, and silver hooks.</d>
    <a>John Donne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="89">
    <d>Could you imagine how horrible things would be if we always told others how we felt? Life would be intolerably bearable. </d>
    <a>Randy K. Milholland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="90">
    <d>Disappointments are to the soul what the thunder-storm is to the air.</d>
    <a>Friedrich von Schiller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="91">
    <d>Dive deep, O mind, dive deep in the ocean of God&apos;s beauty! If you descend to the uttermost depths, there you will find the gem of love.</d>
    <a>Bengali Hymn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="92">
    <d>Do all things with love.</d>
    <a>Og Mandino</a>
  </q>
  <q id="93">
    <d>Do everything with so much love in your heart that you would never want to do it any other way.</d>
    <a>Yogi Desai</a>
  </q>
  <q id="94">
    <d>Do not keep the alabaster boxes of your love and tenderness sealed up until your friends are dead. Fill their lives with sweetness, speak cheering words while their ears can hear, and while their hearts can be thrilled and made happier by them.</d>
    <a>Williams Childs</a>
  </q>
  <q id="95">
    <d>Do not tell me, for I&apos;ve heard it all, there is too much to do with hate, but much more to do with love.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="96">
    <d>Do not think that love in order to be genuine has to be extraordinary. What we need is to love without getting tired. Be faithful in small things because it is in them that your strength lies.</d>
    <a>Mother Theresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="97">
    <d>Do you want to know a good way to fall in love? Just associate with all your pleasant experiences with someone, and disassociate from all the unpleasant ones.</d>
    <a>Richard Bandler</a>
  </q>
  <q id="98">
    <d>Don&apos;t be afraid of showing affection. Be warm and tender, thoughtful and affectionate. Men are more helped by sympathy than by service. Love is more than money, and a kind word will give more pleasure than a present.</d>
    <a>Sir John Lubbock</a>
  </q>
  <q id="99">
    <d>Don&apos;t hold to anger, hurt or pain. They steal your energy and keep you from love.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="100">
    <d>Don&apos;t smother each other. No one can grow in the shade.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="101">
    <d>Ever has it been that love knows not its own depth until the hour of separation.</d>
    <a>Kahlil Gibran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="102">
    <d>Every day I live I am more convinced that the waste of life lies in the love we have not given, the powers we have not used, the selfish prudence that will risk nothing and which, shirking pain, misses happiness as well.</d>
    <a>Mary Cholmondeley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="103">
    <d>Every little girl knows about love. It is only her capacity to suffer because of it that increases.</d>
    <a>Francoise Sagan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="104">
    <d>Every man loves what he is good at.</d>
    <a>Thomas Shadwell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="105">
    <d>Every man needs two women, a quiet home-maker, and a thrilling nymph.</d>
    <a>Iris Murdoch</a>
  </q>
  <q id="106">
    <d>Everybody can be great because anybody can serve. You don&apos;t have to have a college degree to serve. You don&apos;t have to make your subject and verb agree to serve. You only need a heart full of grace. A soul generated by love.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther King</a>
  </q>
  <q id="107">
    <d>Everybody forgets the basic thing; people are not going to love you unless you love them.</d>
    <a>Pat Carroll</a>
  </q>
  <q id="108">
    <d>Everyone admits that love is wonderful and necessary, yet no one agrees on just what it is.</d>
    <a>Diane Ackerman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="109">
    <d>Everyone admits that love is wonderful and necessary, yet no one agrees on just what it is.</d>
    <a>Diane Ackerman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="110">
    <d>Everyone of us needs to show how much we care for each other and, in the process, care for ourselves.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="111">
    <d>Everything comes to us from others. To Be is to belong to someone.</d>
    <a>Jean-Paul Sartre</a>
  </q>
  <q id="112">
    <d>Falling in love consists merely in uncorking the imagination and bottling the common-sense.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="113">
    <d>Falling out of love is chiefly a matter of forgetting how charming someone is.</d>
    <a>Iris Murdoch</a>
  </q>
  <q id="114">
    <d>Fantastic tyrant of the amorous heart. How hard thy yoke, how cruel thy dart. Those escape your anger who refuse your sway, and those are punished most, who most obey.</d>
    <a>Matthew Prior</a>
  </q>
  <q id="115">
    <d>Fantasy love is much better than reality love. Never doing it is very exciting. The most exciting attractions are between two opposites that never meet.</d>
    <a>Andy Warhol</a>
  </q>
  <q id="116">
    <d>First love is only a little foolishness and a lot of curiosity: no really self-respecting woman would take advantage of it.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="117">
    <d>Follow love and it will flee, flee love and it will follow.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="118">
    <d>Footfalls echo in the memoryDown the passage which we did not takeTowards the door we never openedInto the rose-garden.My words echoThus, in your mind.</d>
    <a>TS (Thomas Stearns) Eliot</a>
  </q>
  <q id="119">
    <d>For a crowd is not company; and faces are but a gallery of pictures; and talk but a tinkling cymbal, where there is no love.</d>
    <a>Francis Bacon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="120">
    <d>For in the end, we will conserve only what we love. We will love only what we understand. We will understand only what we are taught.</d>
    <a>Baba Dioum</a>
  </q>
  <q id="121">
    <d>For it is the suffering flesh, it is suffering, it is death, that lovers perpetuate upon the earth. Love is at once the brother, son, and father of death, which is its sister, mother, and daughter. And thus it is that in the depth of love there is a depth</d>
    <a>Miguel de Unamuno</a>
  </q>
  <q id="122">
    <d>For it was not into my ear you whispered, but into my heart. It was not my lips you kissed, but my soul.</d>
    <a>Judy Garland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="123">
    <d>For love... has two faces; one white, the other black; two bodies; one smooth, the other hairy. It has two hands, two feet, two tails, two, indeed, of every member and each one is the exact opposite of the other. Yet, so strictly are they joined together</d>
    <a>Virginia Woolf</a>
  </q>
  <q id="124">
    <d>For one human being to love another: that is perhaps the most difficult of all our tasks, the ultimate, the last test and proof, the work for which all other work is but preparation.</d>
    <a>Rainer Maria Rilke</a>
  </q>
  <q id="125">
    <d>For true love is inexhaustible; the more you give, the more you have. And if you go to draw at the true fountainhead, the more water you draw, the more abundant is its flow.</d>
    <a>Antoine De Saint-Exupery</a>
  </q>
  <q id="126">
    <d>For what is love itself, for the one we love best? An enfolding of immeasurable cares which yet are better than any joys outside our love.</d>
    <a>George Eliot</a>
  </q>
  <q id="127">
    <d>For where there is true love, a man is neither out of measure lifted up by prosperity, nor cast down by mishap; whether you give or take away from him, so long as he keeps his beloved, he has a spring of inward peace. Thus, even though thy outward man grieve, or weep downright, that may well be borne, if only thy inner man remain at peace, perfectly content with the will of God.</d>
    <a>Johannes Tauler</a>
  </q>
  <q id="128">
    <d>For where your treasure is, there your heart will be also.</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="129">
    <d>Forget love - I&apos;d rather fall in chocolate!</d>
    <a>Sandra J. Dykes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="130">
    <d>Friendship often ends in love; but love in friendship - never.</d>
    <a>Charles Caleb Colton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="131">
    <d>Frustrated love has been the incentive for many great works.</d>
    <a>John N. Mitchell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="132">
    <d>Girls, like men, want to be petted, pitied, and made much of, when they are diffident, in low spirits, or in unrequited love. These are services which the weak cannot render to the strong and which the strong will not render to the weak, except when there is also a difference of sex.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="133">
    <d>Go to the truth beyond the mind. Love is the bridge.</d>
    <a>Stephen Levine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="134">
    <d>God loves each of us as if there were only one of us.</d>
    <a>Saint Augustine of Hippo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="135">
    <d>God proved His love on the Cross. When Christ hung, and bled, and died, it was God saying to the world, I love you.</d>
    <a>Billy Graham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="136">
    <d>Gravitation can not be held responsible for people falling in love</d>
    <a>Albert Einstein</a>
  </q>
  <q id="137">
    <d>Gravitation is not responsible for people falling in love.</d>
    <a>Albert Einstein</a>
  </q>
  <q id="138">
    <d>Gravity. It keeps you rooted to the ground. In space, there&apos;s not any gravity. You just kind of leave your feet and go floating around. Is that what being in love is like? </d>
    <a>Josh Brand and John Falsey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="139">
    <d>Great passions, my dear, don&apos;t exist: they&apos;re liars fantasies. What do exist are little loves that may last for a short or a longer while.</d>
    <a>Anna Magnani</a>
  </q>
  <q id="140">
    <d>Grow old along with me!The best is yet to be,The last of life, for which the first was made:Our times are in his hand Who saith,</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="141">
    <d>Hate leaves ugly scars, love leaves beautiful ones.</d>
    <a>Mignon McLaughlin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="142">
    <d>He drew a circle that shut me out-Heretic, rebel, a thing to flout.But Love and I had the wit to win:We drew a circle that took him in.</d>
    <a>Edwin Markham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="143">
    <d>He Freud often said three things were impossible to fulfill completely; healing, education, governing. He limited his goals in analytic treatment to brining the patient to the point where he could work for a living and learn to love.</d>
    <a>Theodor Reik</a>
  </q>
  <q id="144">
    <d>He is not a lover who does not love forever.</d>
    <a>Euripides</a>
  </q>
  <q id="145">
    <d>He that loveth not knoweth not God; for God is love. I John</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="146">
    <d>He that plants trees loves others besides himself.</d>
    <a>English Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="147">
    <d>He who is in love is wise and is becoming wiser, sees newly every time he looks at the object beloved, drawing from it with his eyes and his mind those virtues which it possesses.</d>
    <a>Ralph Waldo Emerson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="148">
    <d>He who is not impatient is not in love.</d>
    <a>Italian Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="149">
    <d>Heaven offers nothing that the mercenary soul can desire. It is safe to tell the pure in heart that they shall see God, for only the pure in heart want to. There are rewards that do not sully motives. A man&apos;s love for a woman is not mercenary because he wants to marry her, nor his love for poetry mercenary because he wants to read it, nor his love of exercise less disinterested because he wants to run and leap and walk. Love, by definition, seeks to enjoy its object.</d>
    <a>C.S. Lewis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="150">
    <d>Honor the ocean of love.</d>
    <a>George De Benneville</a>
  </q>
  <q id="151">
    <d>How do I love thee? Let me count the ways.I love thee to the depth and breadth and heightMy soul can reach, when feeling out of sightFor the ends of Being and ideal Grace.I love thee to the level of every day&apos;sMost quiet need; by sun and candle-light.I love thee freely, as men strive for Right;I love thee purely, as they turn from Praise.I love thee with the passion put to useIn my old griefs, and with my childhood&apos;s faithI love thee with a love I seemed to loseWith my lost saints,-I love thee with the breath.Smiles, tears, of all my life!-and, if God choose,I shall but love thee better after death.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="152">
    <d>How many young men, in all previous times of unprecedented steadiness, had turned suddenly wild and wicked for the same reason, and, in an ecstasy of unrequited love, taken to wrench off door-knockers, and invert the boxes of rheumatic watchmen!</d>
    <a>Charles Dickens</a>
  </q>
  <q id="153">
    <d>How sweet it is to love, and to be dissolved, and as it were to bathe myself in thy love.</d>
    <a>Thomas Kempis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="154">
    <d>How we glow over these novels of passion, when the story is told with any spark of truth and nature! And what fastens attention, in the intercourse of life, like any passage betraying affection between two parties? Perhaps we never saw them before and never shall meet them again. But we see them exchange a glance or betray a deep emotion, and we are no longer strangers. We understand them and take the warmest interest in the development of the romance. All mankind love a lover.</d>
    <a>Ralph Waldo Emerson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="155">
    <d>How we treasure (and admire) the people who acknowledge us! </d>
    <a>Julie Morgenstern</a>
  </q>
  <q id="156">
    <d>However it is debased or misinterpreted, love is a redemptive feature. To focus on one individual so that their desires become superior to yours is a very cleansing experience.</d>
    <a>Jeanette Winterson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="157">
    <d>Human Love... It is that extra creation that stands hurt and baffled at the place of death. Being human, wanting children and sunlight and breath to go on, forever.</d>
    <a>Christopher Leach</a>
  </q>
  <q id="158">
    <d>I adore him I have never been so happy. I have real love.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="159">
    <d>I argue thee that love is life. And life hath immortality.</d>
    <a>Emily Dickinson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="160">
    <d>I believe love produces a certain flowering of the whole personality which nothing else can achieve.</d>
    <a>Ivan Sergeevich</a>
  </q>
  <q id="161">
    <d>I believe the greatest gift I can conceive of having from anyone is to be seen by them, heard by them, to be understood and touched by them.</d>
    <a>Virginia Satir</a>
  </q>
  <q id="162">
    <d>I cannot exist without you - I am forgetful of every thing but seeing you again - my Life seems to stop there - I see no further. You have absorb&apos;d me. I have a sensation at the present moment as though I were dissolving... I have been astonished that Men could die Martyrs for religion - I have shudder&apos;d at it - I shudder no more - I could be martyr&apos;d for my Religion - Love is my religion - I could die for that - I could die for you. My creed is Love and you are its only tenet - You have ravish&apos;d me away by a Power I cannot resist.</d>
    <a>John Keats</a>
  </q>
  <q id="163">
    <d>I define love for our purpose as the passion of one being for another in the hope of being loved in return.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="164">
    <d>I do not love you as if you were salt-rose, or topaz,or the arrow of carnations the fire shoots off.I love you as certain dark things are to be loved,in secret, between the shadow and the soul.</d>
    <a>Pablo Neruda</a>
  </q>
  <q id="165">
    <d>I do not now begin,-I still adore Her whom I early cherish&apos;d in my breast; Then once again with prudence dispossess&apos;d, And to whose heart I&apos;m driven back once more. The love of Petrarch, that all-glorious love, Was unrequited, and, alas, full sad...</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="166">
    <d>I do not think that what is called Love at first sight is so great an absurdity as it is sometimes imagined to be. We generally make up our minds beforehand to the sort of person we should like, grave or gay, black, brown, or fair; with golden tresses or raven locks; - and when we meet with a complete example of the qualities we admire, the bargain is soon struck.</d>
    <a>William Hazlitt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="167">
    <d>I don&apos;t want to live - I want to love first, and live incidentally.</d>
    <a>Zelda Fitzgerald</a>
  </q>
  <q id="168">
    <d>I don&apos;t wish to be everything to everyone, but I would like to be something to someone.</d>
    <a> Javan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="169">
    <d>I fell in love with the thought that a human life could be a priestly conduit, a connecting link between earth and sky. As I grew and stumbled and, most important, as I began to love and be loved, I realized that the ultimate priest is the lover inside us</d>
    <a>Marianne Williamson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="170">
    <d>I hated her now with a hatred more fatal than indifference because it was the other side of love.</d>
    <a>J. August Strindberg</a>
  </q>
  <q id="171">
    <d>I have decided to stick with love. Hate is too great a burden to bear.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther King, Jr.</a>
  </q>
  <q id="172">
    <d>I have found men who didn&apos;t know how to kiss. I&apos;ve always found time to teach them.</d>
    <a>Mae West</a>
  </q>
  <q id="173">
    <d>I have found the paradox that if I love until it hurts, then there is no hurt, but only more love.</d>
    <a>Mother Teresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="174">
    <d>I have found the paradox that if I love until it hurts, then there is no hurt, but only more love.</d>
    <a>Mother Theresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="175">
    <d>I have learned not to worry about love; but to honor its coming with all my heart.</d>
    <a>Alice Walker</a>
  </q>
  <q id="176">
    <d>I hold it true, whatever befall; I feel it, when I sorrow most; &apos;Tis better to have loved and lost Than never to have loved at all.</d>
    <a>Alfred Lord Tennyson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="177">
    <d>I know a love may be revived which absence, inconstancy, or even infidelity has extinguished, but there is no returning from a d?go?t given by satiety.</d>
    <a>Mary Wortley Montagu</a>
  </q>
  <q id="178">
    <d>I know that I can give love for a minute, for half an hour; for a day, for a month, but I can give and I&apos;m very happy to do that and I want to do that.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="179">
    <d>I learnt that men were moved by a savage egoism, that love was only the dirty trick nature played on us to achieve the continuation of the species.</d>
    <a>W. Somerset Maugham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="180">
    <d>I love a hand that meets my own with a grasp that causes some sensation.</d>
    <a>Samuel Osgood</a>
  </q>
  <q id="181">
    <d>I love Brian Piccolo, and I&apos;d like all of you to love him. When you hit your knees to pray tonight, please ask God to love him, too.</d>
    <a>Gale Sayers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="182">
    <d>I love Mickey Mouse more than any woman I have ever known.</d>
    <a>Walt Disney</a>
  </q>
  <q id="183">
    <d>I love thee with a love I seemed to lose With my lost saints, - I love thee with the breath, Smiles, tears, of all my life! - and, if God choose, I shall but love thee better after death.</d>
    <a>Elisabeth Barrett Browning</a>
  </q>
  <q id="184">
    <d>I love to hold people&apos;s hands when I visit hospitals, even though they are shocked because they haven&apos;t experienced anything like it before, but to me it is a normal thing to do.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="185">
    <d>I love you, not for what you are, but for what I am when I am with you.</d>
    <a>Roy Croft</a>
  </q>
  <q id="186">
    <d>I met in the street a very poor young man who was in love. His hat was old, his coat worn, his cloak was out at the elbows, the water passed through his shoes - and the stars through his soul.</d>
    <a>Victor Hugo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="187">
    <d>I never knew how to worship until I knew how to love.</d>
    <a>Henry Ward Beecher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="188">
    <d>I never loved another person the way I loved myself.</d>
    <a>Mae West</a>
  </q>
  <q id="189">
    <d>I pray Thee, O God, that I may be beautiful within.</d>
    <a>Socrates</a>
  </q>
  <q id="190">
    <d>I promise to love you forever - every single day of forever.</d>
    <a>Stephenie Meyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="191">
    <d>I regard as a mortal sin not only the lying of the senses in matters of love, but also the illusion which the senses seek to create where love is only partial. I say, I believe, that one must love with all of one&apos;s being, or else live, come what may, a life of complete chastity.</d>
    <a>George Sand</a>
  </q>
  <q id="192">
    <d>I remember when I used to sit on hospital beds and hold people?s hands, people used to be shocked because they?d never seen this before. To me it was quite normal.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="193">
    <d>I shall always be a priest of love.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="194">
    <d>I try to give to the poor people for love what the rich could get for money. No, I wouldn&apos;t touch a leper for a thousand pounds; yet I willingly cure him for the love of God.</d>
    <a>Mother Theresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="195">
    <d>I was nauseous and tingly all over. I was either in love or I had smallpox.</d>
    <a>Woody Allen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="196">
    <d>I was never one to patiently pick up broken fragments and glue them together again and tell myself that the mended whole was as good as new. What is broken is broken - and I&apos;d rather remember it as it was at its best than mend it and see the broken pieces as long as I lived.</d>
    <a>Margaret Mitchell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="197">
    <d>I would not miss your face, your neck, your hands, your limbs, your bosom and certain other of your charms. Indeed, not to become boring by naming them all, I could do without you, Chloe, altogether.</d>
    <a>Marcus Valerius Martial</a>
  </q>
  <q id="198">
    <d>I would rather live and love where death is king than have eternal life where love is not.</d>
    <a>Robert G. Ingersoll</a>
  </q>
  <q id="199">
    <d>I&apos;d like to run away From you, But if you didn&apos;t come And find me... I would die.</d>
    <a>Shirley Bassey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="200">
    <d>If a woman doesn&apos;t chase a man a little, she doesn&apos;t love him.</d>
    <a>Edward W. Howe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="201">
    <d>If I could dream at all it would be about you. And I&apos;m not ashamed of it.</d>
    <a>Stephenie Meyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="202">
    <d>If I had a single flower for every time I think about you, I could walk forever in my garden.</d>
    <a>Claudia Ghandi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="203">
    <d>If I love you Wednesday, What is that to you? I do not love you Thursday - so much is true.</d>
    <a>Edna St. Vincent Millay</a>
  </q>
  <q id="204">
    <d>If I love you, what business is it of yours?</d>
    <a>Johann von Goethe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="205">
    <d>If I place love above everything, it is because for me it is the most desperate, the most despairing state of affairs imaginable.</d>
    <a>Andre Breton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="206">
    <d>If it is your time, love will track you down like a cruise missile.</d>
    <a>Lynda Barry</a>
  </q>
  <q id="207">
    <d>If love is shelter, I&apos;m going to walk in the rain.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="208">
    <d>If love is the answer, could you please rephrase the question?</d>
    <a>Lily Tomlin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="209">
    <d>If love means that one person absorbs the other, then no real relationship exists any more. Love evaporates; there is nothing left to love. The integrity of self is gone.</d>
    <a>Ann Oakley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="210">
    <d>If marriage is your object, you&apos;d better start loving your subject.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="211">
    <d>If only one could tell true love from false love as one can tell mushrooms from toadstools.</d>
    <a>Katherine Mansfield</a>
  </q>
  <q id="212">
    <d>If only the strength of the love that people feel when it is reciprocated could be as intense and obsessive as the love we feel when it is not; then marriages would be truly made in heaven.</d>
    <a>Ben Elton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="213">
    <d>If somebody says, I love you, to me, I feel as though I had a pistol pointed at my head. What can anybody reply under such conditions but that which the pistol-holder requires? I love you, too.</d>
    <a>Kurt Vonnegut</a>
  </q>
  <q id="214">
    <d>If there is any country on earth where the course of true love may be expected to run smooth, it is America.</d>
    <a>Harriet Martineau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="215">
    <d>If there is anything better than to be loved it is loving.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="216">
    <d>If there&apos;s delight in love, &apos;Tis when I see that heart, which others bleed for, bleed for me.</d>
    <a>William Congreve</a>
  </q>
  <q id="217">
    <d>If we discovered we only had five minutes left to say all we wanted to say, every telephone booth would be occupied by people telling other people that they loved them.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="218">
    <d>If we love our country, we should also love our countrymen.</d>
    <a>Ronald Reagan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="219">
    <d>If we seek the pleasures of love, passion should be occasional, and common sense continual.</d>
    <a>Robertson Davies</a>
  </q>
  <q id="220">
    <d>If you cannot inspire a woman with love of you, fill her above the brim with love of herself; all that runs over will be yours.</d>
    <a>Charles Caleb Colton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="221">
    <d>If you could only love enough, you could be the most powerful person in the world.</d>
    <a>Emmet Fox</a>
  </q>
  <q id="222">
    <d>If you find someone you love in your life, then hang on to that love.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="223">
    <d>If you had it all to do over, would you fall in love with yourself again?</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="224">
    <d>If you have it Love, you don&apos;t need to have anything else, and if you don&apos;t have it, it doesn&apos;t matter much what else you have.</d>
    <a>James Barrie</a>
  </q>
  <q id="225">
    <d>If you judge people, you have no time to love them.</d>
    <a>Mother Theresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="226">
    <d>If you love somebody, let them go. If they return, they were always yours. If they don&apos;t, they never were.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="227">
    <d>If you love something let it go free. If it doesn&apos;t come back, you never had it. If it comes back, love it forever.</d>
    <a>Doug Horton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="228">
    <d>If you loved someone, you couldn&apos;t let lies come between you. No matter what happened - even if you&apos;d already lost each other forever - you owed each other the truth.</d>
    <a>Claudia Gray</a>
  </q>
  <q id="229">
    <d>If you say, I love you, then you have already fallen in love with language, which is already a form of break up and infidelity.</d>
    <a>Jean Baudrillard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="230">
    <d>If you value a man&apos;s regard, strive with him. As to liking, you like your newspaper - and despise it.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="231">
    <d>If you were going to die soon and had only one phone call you could make, who would you call and what would you say? And why are you waiting?</d>
    <a>Stephen Levine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="232">
    <d>If you wish to be loved; Love!</d>
    <a>Seneca (Seneca the Elder)</a>
  </q>
  <q id="233">
    <d>Immature love says: &apos;I love you because I need you.&apos; Mature love says &apos;I need you because I love you.&apos;</d>
    <a>Erich Fromm</a>
  </q>
  <q id="234">
    <d>In a great romance, each person plays a part the other really likes.</d>
    <a>Elizabeth Ashley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="235">
    <d>In a separation it is the one who is not really in loved who says the more tender things.</d>
    <a>Marcel Proust</a>
  </q>
  <q id="236">
    <d>In dreams and in love there are no impossibilities.</d>
    <a>Janos Arany</a>
  </q>
  <q id="237">
    <d>In every loving woman there is a priestess of the past - a pious guardian of some affection, of which the object has disappeared.</d>
    <a>Henri-Fr?d?ric Amiel</a>
  </q>
  <q id="238">
    <d>In every question and every remark tossed back and forth between lovers who have not played out the last fugue, there is one question and it is this: Is there someone new?</d>
    <a>Edna O&apos;Brien</a>
  </q>
  <q id="239">
    <d>In love the paradox occurs that two beings become one and yet remain two.</d>
    <a>Erich Fromm</a>
  </q>
  <q id="240">
    <d>In love there are two things - bodies and words.</d>
    <a>Joyce Carol Oates</a>
  </q>
  <q id="241">
    <d>In love, as in gluttony, pleasure is a matter of the utmost precision.</d>
    <a>Italo Calvino</a>
  </q>
  <q id="242">
    <d>In love, there is always one who kisses and one who offers the cheek.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="243">
    <d>In love, unlike most other passions, the recollection of what you have had and lost is always better than what you can hope for in the future.</d>
    <a>Henri B. Stendhal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="244">
    <d>In nine cases out of ten, a woman had better show more affection than she feels.</d>
    <a>Jane Austen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="245">
    <d>
      In real love you want the other person&apos;s good. In romantic love you
      want the other person.
    </d>
    <a>Margaret Anderson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="246">
    <d>In real love you want the other person&apos;s good. In romantic love, you want the other person.</d>
    <a>Margaret Anderson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="247">
    <d>In the absence of love, there is nothing worth fighting for.</d>
    <a>Elijah Wood</a>
  </q>
  <q id="248">
    <d>In the attic, a warhead no doubt burns. Everything is combustible. Faith burns. Trust burns. Everything burns to nothing and even nothing burns. . . . And when there is nothing, there is nothing worth dying for and when there is nothing worth dying for, there is only nothing.</d>
    <a>Tim O&apos;Brien</a>
  </q>
  <q id="249">
    <d>In the cold change which time hath wrought on love(The snowy winter of his summer prime),Should a chance sigh or sudden tear-drop moveThy heart to memory of the olden time;Turn not to gaze on me with pitying eyes,Nor mock me with a withered hope renewed;But from the bower we both have loved, ariseAnd leave me to my barren solitude!What boots it that a momentary flameShoots from the ashes of a dying fire?We gaze upon the hearth from whence it came,And know the exhausted embers must expire:Therefore no pity, or my heart will break;Be cold, be careless-for thy past love&apos;s sake!</d>
    <a>Caroline Norton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="250">
    <d>In the evening of life, we will be judged on love alone.</d>
    <a>Saint John of the Cross</a>
  </q>
  <q id="251">
    <d>In the long run all love is paid by love, Though undervalued by the hosts of earth; The great eternal Government above Keeps strict account and will redeem its worth. Give thy love freely; do not count the cost; So beautiful a thing was never lostIn the long run.</d>
    <a>Ella Wheeler Wilcox</a>
  </q>
  <q id="252">
    <d>Infinite hungers leap no more I in the chance swaying of your dress; and love has changed to kindliness.</d>
    <a>Rupert Brooke</a>
  </q>
  <q id="253">
    <d>Is it not by love alone that we succeed in penetrating to the very essence of being?</d>
    <a>Igor Stravinsky</a>
  </q>
  <q id="254">
    <d>Is love supposed to last throughout all time, or is it like trains changing at random stops. If I loved her, how could I leave her? If I felt that way then, how come I don&apos;t feel anything now? </d>
    <a>Jeff Melvoin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="255">
    <d>It has ever been since time began, and ever will be, till time lose breath, that love is a mood -no more -to man, and love to a woman is life or death.</d>
    <a>Ella Wheeler Wilcox</a>
  </q>
  <q id="256">
    <d>It is a beautiful trait in the lovers character, that they think no evil of the object loved.</d>
    <a>Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</a>
  </q>
  <q id="257">
    <d>It is at the edge of a petal that love waits.</d>
    <a>William Carlos Williams</a>
  </q>
  <q id="258">
    <d>It is better to be hated for who you are than to be loved for what you are not.</d>
    <a>Andre Gide</a>
  </q>
  <q id="259">
    <d>It is better to have loved and lost than never to have lost at all.</d>
    <a>Samuel Butler</a>
  </q>
  <q id="260">
    <d>It is better to have loved and lost, than to have paid for it and not liked it at all.</d>
    <a>Graham Davies</a>
  </q>
  <q id="261">
    <d>It is better to have loved your wife than never to have loved at all.</d>
    <a>Edgar Saltus</a>
  </q>
  <q id="262">
    <d>It is by loving and by being loved that one can come nearest to the soul of another.</d>
    <a>George Mcdonald</a>
  </q>
  <q id="263">
    <d>It is difficult to know at what moment love begins; it is less difficult to know that it has begun.</d>
    <a>Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</a>
  </q>
  <q id="264">
    <d>It is difficult to lay aside a confirmed passion.</d>
    <a>Catullus</a>
  </q>
  <q id="265">
    <d>It is easier to guard a sack full of fleas than a girl in love.</d>
    <a>Yiddish Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="266">
    <d>It is easier to keep half a dozen lovers guessing than to keep one lover after he has stopped guessing.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="267">
    <d>It is easy to halve the potato where there is love.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="268">
    <d>It is here, my daughters, that love is to be found - not hidden away in corners but in the midst of occasions of sin. And believe me, although we may more often fail and commit small lapses, our gain will be incomparably the greater.</d>
    <a>Teresa of Avila</a>
  </q>
  <q id="269">
    <d>It is not a lack of love, but a lack of friendship that makes unhappy marriages.</d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="270">
    <d>It is remarkable how similar the pattern of love is to the pattern of insanity.</d>
    <a>The Matrix - Revolutions</a>
  </q>
  <q id="271">
    <d>It is the privilege of those who fear love to murder those who do not fear it!</d>
    <a>May Sarton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="272">
    <d>
      It is the things in common
      that make relationships enjoyable,
      but it is the little differences
      that make them interesting.
    </d>
    <a>Todd Ruthman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="273">
    <d>It is unfortunately very true that, without leisure and money, love can be no more than an orgy of the common man. Instead of being a sudden impulse full of ardor and reverie, it becomes a distastefully utilitarian affair.</d>
    <a>Charles Baudelaire</a>
  </q>
  <q id="274">
    <d>It is well to be happy and wise and well to be honest and true; it is well to be off with the old love, before you are on with the new.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="275">
    <d>It is with true love as it is with ghosts; everyone talks about it, but few have seen it.</d>
    <a>Fran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="276">
    <d>It is wrong to think that love comes from long companionship and persevering courtship. Love is the offspring of spiritual affinity and unless that affinity is created in a moment, it will not be created for years or even generations.</d>
    <a>Kahlil Gibran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="277">
    <d>It makes no difference how deeply seated may be the trouble, how hopeless the outlook, how muddled the tangle, how great the mistake. A sufficient realization of love will dissolve it all.</d>
    <a>Emmet Fox</a>
  </q>
  <q id="278">
    <d>It was all love on my side, and all good comradeship and friendship on hers. When we parted she was a free woman, but I could never again be a free man.</d>
    <a>Sir Arthur Conan Doyle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="279">
    <d>It&apos;s afterwards you realize that the feeling of happiness you had with a man didn&apos;t necessarily prove that you loved him.</d>
    <a>Marguerite Duras</a>
  </q>
  <q id="280">
    <d>It&apos;s unthinkable not to love -you&apos;d have a severe nervous breakdown. Or you&apos;d have to be Philip Larkin.</d>
    <a>Lawrence Durrell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="281">
    <d>I&apos;ve only been in love with a beer bottle and a mirror.</d>
    <a>Sid Vicious</a>
  </q>
  <q id="282">
    <d>Keep love in your heart. A life without it is like a sunless garden when the flowers are dead.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="283">
    <d>Keep me as the apple of the eye, hide me under the shadow of thy wings.</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="284">
    <d>Learning to love yourself is the greatest love of all. </d>
    <a>Michael Masser and Linda Creed</a>
  </q>
  <q id="285">
    <d>Let no one believe that he has received the divine kiss, if he knows the truth without loving it or loves it without understanding it. But blessed is that kiss whereby not only is God recognized but also the Father is loved; for there is never full knowledge without perfect love.</d>
    <a>St. Bernard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="286">
    <d>Let the first impulse pass, wait for the second.</d>
    <a>Baltasar Gracian</a>
  </q>
  <q id="287">
    <d>Let the lover be disgraceful, crazy, absent-minded. Someone sober will worry about events going badly. Let the lover be.</d>
    <a>Rumi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="288">
    <d>Life and love are life and love, a bunch of violets is a bunch of violets, and to drag in the idea of a point is to ruin everything. Live and let live, love and let love, flower and fade, and follow the natural curve, which flows on, pointless.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="289">
    <d>Life has taught us that love does not consist in gazing at each other but in looking outward together in the same direction.</d>
    <a>Antoine de Saint-Exup?ry</a>
  </q>
  <q id="290">
    <d>Life in abundance comes only through great love.</d>
    <a>Elbert Hubbard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="291">
    <d>Life is the flower for which love is the honey.</d>
    <a>Victor Hugo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="292">
    <d>Life without love is like a tree without blossoms or fruit.</d>
    <a>Kahlil Gibran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="293">
    <d>Listen! Encourage. Say something. Do something. Be yourself. Love</d>
    <a>Rev. Dale Turner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="294">
    <d>Live for love. Without love, you don&apos;t live.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="295">
    <d>Looking back, I have this to regret, that too often when I loved, I did not say so.</d>
    <a>Ray Stannard Baker [David Grayson]</a>
  </q>
  <q id="296">
    <d>Love - a wildly misunderstood although highly desirable malfunction of the heart which weakens the brain, causes eyes to sparkle, cheeks to glow, blood pressure to rise and the lips to pucker</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="297">
    <d>Love - THE FEELING - is a fruit of love, the verb.</d>
    <a>Stephen Covey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="298">
    <d>Love (understood as the desire of good for another) is in fact so unnatural a phenomenon that it can scarcely repeat itself, the soul being unable to become virgin again and not having energy enough to cast itself out again into the ocean of another&apos;s soul.</d>
    <a>James Joyce</a>
  </q>
  <q id="299">
    <d>Love all that has been created by God, both the whole and every grain of sand. Love every leaf and every ray of light. Love the beasts and the birds, love the plants, love every separate fragment. If you love each fragment, you will understand the mystery of the whole resting in God.</d>
    <a>Fyodor Dostoyevsky</a>
  </q>
  <q id="300">
    <d>Love all, trust a few. Do wrong to none. </d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="301">
    <d>Love alone can unite living beings so as to complete and fulfill them... for it alone joins them by what is deepest in themselves. All we need is to imagine our ability to love developing until it embraces the totality of men and the earth.</d>
    <a>Pierre Teilhard de Chardin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="302">
    <d>Love alone could waken love.</d>
    <a>Pearl Buck</a>
  </q>
  <q id="303">
    <d>Love and a cough cannot be hid.</d>
    <a>George Herbert</a>
  </q>
  <q id="304">
    <d>
      Love and electricity are one in the same, my dear. If you do not feel the jolt in your soul every time a kiss is shared, a whisper is
      spoken, a touch is felt, then your not really in love at all.
    </d>
    <a>C. J. Franks</a>
  </q>
  <q id="305">
    <d>Love and pity and wish well to every soul in the world; dwell in love, and then you dwell in God.</d>
    <a>William Law</a>
  </q>
  <q id="306">
    <d>Love and work are the cornerstones of our humanness.</d>
    <a>Sigmund Freud</a>
  </q>
  <q id="307">
    <d>Love and you shall be loved. All love is mathematically just, as much as the two sides of an algebraic equation.</d>
    <a>Ralph Waldo Emerson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="308">
    <d>Love bears it out even to the edge of doom.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="309">
    <d>Love begins at home, and it is not how much we do... but how much love we put in that action.</d>
    <a>Mother Theresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="310">
    <d>Love builds bridges where there are none.</d>
    <a>R. H. Delaney</a>
  </q>
  <q id="311">
    <d>Love built on beauty, soon as beauty, dies.</d>
    <a>John Donne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="312">
    <d>Love can make you do things that you never thought possible.</d>
    <a>Phil Collins</a>
  </q>
  <q id="313">
    <d>Love can neither be bought or sold, its only price is love.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="314">
    <d>Love can never grow old. Locks may lose their brown and gold. Cheeks may fade and hollow grow. But the hearts that love will know, never winter&apos;s frost and chill, summer&apos;s warmth is in them still.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="315">
    <d>Love can sometimes be magic. But magic can sometimes...just be an illusion.</d>
    <a>Javan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="316">
    <d>Love ceases to be a pleasure, when it ceases to be a secret.</d>
    <a>Aphra Behn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="317">
    <d>Love comes from blindness, friendship from knowledge.</d>
    <a>Comte DeBussy-Rabutin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="318">
    <d>Love comes when manipulation stops; when you think more about the other person than about his or her reactions to you. When you dare to reveal yourself fully. When you dare to be vulnerable.</d>
    <a>Joyce Brothers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="319">
    <d>Love conquers all; let us surrender to Love.</d>
    <a>Virgil</a>
  </q>
  <q id="320">
    <d>Love consists not in feeling great things but in having great detachment and in suffering for the Beloved.</d>
    <a>Saint John of the Cross</a>
  </q>
  <q id="321">
    <d>Love cures people - both the ones who give it and the ones who receive it.</d>
    <a>Karl Menninger</a>
  </q>
  <q id="322">
    <d>Love does not begin and end the way we seem to think it does. Love is a battle, love is a war; love is a growing up.</d>
    <a>James Baldwin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="323">
    <d>Love does not consist in gazing at each other, but in looking outward together in the same direction.</d>
    <a>Antoine De Saint-Exupery</a>
  </q>
  <q id="324">
    <d>Love doesn&apos;t just sit there like a stone; it has to be made, like bread, remade all the time, made new.</d>
    <a>Ursula K. LeGuin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="325">
    <d>
      Love doesn&apos;t make the world go round,
      Love is what makes the ride worthwhile.
    </d>
    <a>Franklin P. Jones</a>
  </q>
  <q id="326">
    <d>Love doesn&apos;t make the world go round. Love is what makes the ride worthwhile.</d>
    <a>Franklin P. Jones</a>
  </q>
  <q id="327">
    <d>Love ever gives. Forgives outlives. And ever stands with open hands. And while it lives, it gives. For this is love&apos;s prerogatives - to give, and give, and give.</d>
    <a>John Oxenham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="328">
    <d>Love expands.</d>
    <a>Hugh Prather</a>
  </q>
  <q id="329">
    <d>Love feels no burden, regards not labors, strives toward more than it attains, argues not of impossibility, since it believes that it may and can do all things. Therefore it avails for all things, and fulfils and accomplishes much where one not a lover falls and lies helpless.</d>
    <a>Thomas Kempis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="330">
    <d>Love feels no burden, thinks nothing of trouble, attempts what is above its strength.... It is therefore able to undertake all things, and it completes many things, and warrants them to take effect, where he who does not love would faint and lie down.</d>
    <a>Thomas Kempis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="331">
    <d>Love floods us with hope.</d>
    <a>Jareb Teague</a>
  </q>
  <q id="332">
    <d>Love gives itself; it is not bought.</d>
    <a>Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</a>
  </q>
  <q id="333">
    <d>Love gives naught but itself and takes naught but from itself. Love possesses not nor would it be possessed; For love is sufficient unto love.</d>
    <a>Kahlil Gibran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="334">
    <d>Love grows by giving. The love we give away is the only love we keep. The only way to retain love is to give it away.</d>
    <a>Elbert Hubbard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="335">
    <d>Love has features which pierce all hearts, he wears a bandage which conceals the faults of those beloved. He has wings, he comes quickly and flies away the same.</d>
    <a> Voltaire</a>
  </q>
  <q id="336">
    <d>Love has no errors, for all errors are the want for love.</d>
    <a>William Law</a>
  </q>
  <q id="337">
    <d>Love has nothing to do with what you are expecting to get, it&apos;s what you are expected to give - which is everything.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="338">
    <d>Love has nothing to do with what you are expecting to get-only with what you are expecting to give-which is everything.</d>
    <a>Katharine Hepburn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="339">
    <d>Love in marriage should be the accomplishment of a beautiful dream, and not, as it too often is, the end.</d>
    <a>Alphonse Karr</a>
  </q>
  <q id="340">
    <d>Love is a better teacher than duty.</d>
    <a>Albert Einstein</a>
  </q>
  <q id="341">
    <d>Love is a canvas furnished by Nature and embroidered by imagination.</d>
    <a>Voltaire (Francois-Marie Arouet)</a>
  </q>
  <q id="342">
    <d>Love is a choice you make from moment to moment.</d>
    <a>Barbara de Angelis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="343">
    <d>Love is a conflict between reflexes and reflections.</d>
    <a>Mangnu Hirschfield</a>
  </q>
  <q id="344">
    <d>Love is a fire. But whether it is going to warm your hearth or burn down your house, you can never tell.</d>
    <a>Joan Crawford</a>
  </q>
  <q id="345">
    <d>Love is a force more formidable than any other. It is invisible - it cannot be seen or measured, yet it is powerful enough to transform you in a moment, and offer you more joy than any material possession could.</d>
    <a>Barbara De Angelis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="346">
    <d>Love is a friendship set to music.</d>
    <a>E. Joseph Cossman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="347">
    <d>Love is a friendship set to music.</d>
    <a>Eli Joseph Cossman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="348">
    <d>Love is a game that two can play and both win.</d>
    <a>Eva Gabor</a>
  </q>
  <q id="349">
    <d>Love is a gift from God, and as we obey His laws and genuinely learn to serve others, we develop God&apos;s love in our lives. Love of God is the means of unlocking divine powers which help us to live worthily and to overcome the world.</d>
    <a>David B. Haight</a>
  </q>
  <q id="350">
    <d>Love is a given, hatred is acquired.</d>
    <a>Doug Horton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="351">
    <d>Love is a great beautifier.</d>
    <a>Louisa May Alcott</a>
  </q>
  <q id="352">
    <d>
      Love is a haunting melody
      That I have never mastered
      And I fear I never will.
    </d>
    <a>William S. Burroughs</a>
  </q>
  <q id="353">
    <d>Love is a ocean of emotions entirely surrounded by expenses.</d>
    <a>Lord Drewar</a>
  </q>
  <q id="354">
    <d>Love is a perky elf dancing a merry little jig and then suddenly he turns on you with a miniature machine gun.</d>
    <a>Matt Groening</a>
  </q>
  <q id="355">
    <d>Love is a promise, love is a souvenir, once given never forgotten, never let it disappear.</d>
    <a>John Lennon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="356">
    <d>Love is a smoke made with the fume of sighs. Being purged, a fire sparkling in lovers eyes. Being vexed, a sea nourished with lovers tears. What is it else? A madness most discreet, a choking gall and a preserving sweet.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="357">
    <d>Love is a spendthrift, leaves it arithmetic at home, is always in the red.</d>
    <a>Paul Scherer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="358">
    <d>Love is a state in which a man sees things most decidedly as they are not.</d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="359">
    <d>Love is a tyrant sparing none.</d>
    <a>Pierre Corneille</a>
  </q>
  <q id="360">
    <d>
      Love is a wonderful thing.
      You never have to take it away
      From one person to give it to another.
      There&apos;s always more than enough to go around.
    </d>
    <a>Pamela de Roy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="361">
    <d>Love is all we have, the only way that each can help the other.</d>
    <a>Euripides</a>
  </q>
  <q id="362">
    <d>Love is all you need.</d>
    <a>Paul McCartney</a>
  </q>
  <q id="363">
    <d>Love is always open arms. If you close your arms about love you will find that you are left holding only yourself.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="364">
    <d>Love is an act of endless forgiveness, a tender look which becomes a habit.</d>
    <a>Peter Ustinov</a>
  </q>
  <q id="365">
    <d>Love is an alliance of friendship and animalism; if the former predominates it is passion exalted and refined; if the latter, gross and sensual.</d>
    <a>Charles Caleb Colton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="366">
    <d>Love is an emotion experienced by the many and enjoyed by the few.</d>
    <a>George Jean Nathan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="367">
    <d>Love is an emotion that is based on an opinion of women that is impossible for those who have had any experience with them.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="368">
    <d>Love is an expression and assertion of self-esteem, a response to one&apos;s own values in the person of another. One gains a profoundly personal, selfish joy from the mere existence of the person one loves. It is one&apos;s own personal, selfish happiness that one seeks, earns, and derives from love.</d>
    <a>Ayn Rand</a>
  </q>
  <q id="369">
    <d>Love is an ideal thing, marriage a real thing; a confusion of the real with the ideal never goes unpunished.</d>
    <a>Johann von Goethe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="370">
    <d>Love is an irresistible desire to be irresistibly desired.</d>
    <a>Robert Frost</a>
  </q>
  <q id="371">
    <d>Love is an ocean of emotions entirely surrounded by expenses.</d>
    <a>Lord Thomas Dewar</a>
  </q>
  <q id="372">
    <d>Love is as much of an object as an obsession, everybody wants it, everybody seeks it, but few ever achieve it, those who do will cherish it, be lost in it, and among all, never... never forget it.</d>
    <a>Curtis Judalet</a>
  </q>
  <q id="373">
    <d>Love is being stupid together.</d>
    <a>Paul Valery</a>
  </q>
  <q id="374">
    <d>Love is blind.</d>
    <a>Chaucer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="375">
    <d>Love is but the discovery of ourselves in others, and the delight in the recognition.</d>
    <a>Alexander Smith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="376">
    <d>Love is composed of a single soul inhabiting two bodies.</d>
    <a> Aristotle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="377">
    <d>Love is composed of a single soul inhabiting two bodies.</d>
    <a>Aristotle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="378">
    <d>Love is everything. It is the key to life, and its influences are those that move the world.</d>
    <a>Ralph Waldo Trine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="379">
    <d>Love is free; to promise for ever to love the same woman is not less absurd than to promise to believe the same creed; such a vow in both cases excludes us from all inquiry.</d>
    <a>Percy Bysshe Shelley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="380">
    <d>Love is inseparable from knowledge.</d>
    <a>St. Macarius of Egypt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="381">
    <d>Love is just a system for getting someone to call you darling after sex.</d>
    <a>Julian Barnes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="382">
    <d>Love is life. All, everything that I understand, I understand only because I love. Everything is, everything exists, only because I love. Everything is united by it alone. Love is God, and to die means that I, a particle of love, shall return to the general and eternal source.</d>
    <a>Leo Tolstoy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="383">
    <d>Love is life. And if you miss love, you miss life.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="384">
    <d>Love is life&apos;s end, but never ending. Love is life&apos;s wealth, never spent, but ever spending. Love&apos;s life&apos;s reward, rewarded in rewarding.</d>
    <a>Herbert Spencer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="385">
    <d>Love is like a fruit. It may look good, but you shouldn&apos;t bite in it until it&apos;s ripe.</d>
    <a>Nick Hertl</a>
  </q>
  <q id="386">
    <d>Love is like a poisonous mushroom - you don&apos;t know if it is the real thing until it is too late</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="387">
    <d>Love is like an hourglass, with the heart filling up as the brain empties.</d>
    <a>Jules Renard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="388">
    <d>Love is like pi - natural, irrational, and very important.</d>
    <a>Lisa Hoffman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="389">
    <d>Love is like quicksilver in the hand. Leave the fingers open and it stays. Clutch it, and it darts away.</d>
    <a>Dorothy Parker</a>
  </q>
  <q id="390">
    <d>Love is love&apos;s reward.</d>
    <a>John Dryden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="391">
    <d>Love is made by two people, in different kinds of solitude. It can be in a crowd, but in an oblivious crowd.</d>
    <a>Louis Aragon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="392">
    <d>Love is missing someone whenever you&apos;re apart, but somehow feeling warm inside because you&apos;re close in heart.</d>
    <a>Kay Knudsen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="393">
    <d>Love is misunderstood to be an emotion; actually, it is a state of awareness, a way of being in the world, a way of seeing oneself and others.</d>
    <a>David R. Hawkins</a>
  </q>
  <q id="394">
    <d>Love is most nearly itself when here and now cease to matter.</d>
    <a>TS (Thomas Stearns) Eliot</a>
  </q>
  <q id="395">
    <d>Love is much like a wild rose, beautiful and calm, but willing to draw blood in its defense.</d>
    <a>Mark Overby</a>
  </q>
  <q id="396">
    <d>Love is much nicer to be in than an automobile accident, a tight girdle, a higher tax bracket, or a holding pattern over Philadelphia.</d>
    <a>Judith Viorst</a>
  </q>
  <q id="397">
    <d>Love is never lost. If not reciprocated, it will flow back and soften and purify the heart.</d>
    <a>Washington Irving</a>
  </q>
  <q id="398">
    <d>Love is not a matter of counting the years - it&apos;s making the years count.</d>
    <a>Wolfman Jack Smith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="399">
    <d>Love is not a matter of counting the years... But making the years count.</d>
    <a>Michelle St. Amand</a>
  </q>
  <q id="400">
    <d>Love is not altogether a delirium, yet it has many points in common therewith.</d>
    <a>Thomas Carlyle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="401">
    <d>Love is not blind - it sees more, not less. But because it sees more, it is willing to see less.</d>
    <a>Rabbi J. Gordon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="402">
    <d>Love is not enough. It must be the foundation, the cornerstone - but not the complete structure. It is much too pliable, too yielding.</d>
    <a>Bette Davis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="403">
    <d>Love is not in our choice but in our fate.</d>
    <a>John Dryden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="404">
    <d>Love is not just looking at each other, it&apos;s looking in the same direction.</d>
    <a>Antoine De Saint-Exupery</a>
  </q>
  <q id="405">
    <d>Love is not love that alters when it alteration finds.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="406">
    <d>Love is not love until love&apos;s vulnerable.</d>
    <a>Theodore Roethke</a>
  </q>
  <q id="407">
    <d>Love is not only something you feel. It&apos;s something you do.</d>
    <a>David Wilkerson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="408">
    <d>Love is not the dying moan of a distant violin-it&apos;s the triumphant twang of a bedspring.</d>
    <a>S. J. Perelman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="409">
    <d>Love is not to be purchased, and affection has no price.</d>
    <a>St. Jerome</a>
  </q>
  <q id="410">
    <d>Love is often nothing but a favorable exchange between two people who get the most of what they can expect, considering their value on the personality market.</d>
    <a>Erich Fromm</a>
  </q>
  <q id="411">
    <d>Love is only the game that is not called on account of darkness.</d>
    <a>Mangnu Hirschfield</a>
  </q>
  <q id="412">
    <d>Love is or it ain&apos;t. Thin love ain&apos;t love at all. </d>
    <a>Toni Morrison</a>
  </q>
  <q id="413">
    <d>Love is patient and kind; love is not jealous or boastful; it is not arrogant or rude. I Corinthians</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="414">
    <d>Love is patient and kind; love is not jealous or boastful; it is not arrogant or rude. Love does not insist on its own way; it is not irritable or resentful; it does not rejoice at wrong, but rejoices in the right. Love bears all things, believes all things, hopes all things.</d>
    <a> Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="415">
    <d>Love is rarer than genius itself. And friendship is rarer than love.</d>
    <a>Charles Peguy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="416">
    <d>Love is said to be blind, but I know some fellows in love who can see twice as much in their sweethearts as I do.</d>
    <a>Josh Billings</a>
  </q>
  <q id="417">
    <d>Love is seeing without eyes, hearing without ears; hatred is nothing.</d>
    <a>Doug Horton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="418">
    <d>Love is shown in your deeds, not in your words.</d>
    <a>Fr. Jerome Cummings</a>
  </q>
  <q id="419">
    <d>Love is something eternal; the aspect may change, but not the essence.</d>
    <a>Vincent Van Gogh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="420">
    <d>Love is staying up all night with a sick child - or a healthy adult.</d>
    <a>Sir David Paradine Frost</a>
  </q>
  <q id="421">
    <d>Love is stronger than justice.</d>
    <a>Sting</a>
  </q>
  <q id="422">
    <d>Love is stronger than violence.</d>
    <a>Hermann Hesse</a>
  </q>
  <q id="423">
    <d>Love is swift, sincere, pious, joyful, generous, strong, patient, faithful, prudent, long-suffering, courageous, and never seeking its own; for wheresoever a person seeketh his own, there he falleth from love.</d>
    <a>Thomas Kempis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="424">
    <d>Love is that condition in which the happiness of another person is essential to your own.</d>
    <a>Robert A. Heinlein</a>
  </q>
  <q id="425">
    <d>Love is the ability and willingness to allow those that you care for to be what they choose for themselves, without any insistence that they satisfy you.</d>
    <a>Wayne Dyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="426">
    <d>Love is the affinity which links and draws together the elements of the world... Love, in fact, is the agent of universal synthesis.</d>
    <a>Pierre Teilhard de Chardin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="427">
    <d>Love is the big booming beat which covers up the noise of hate. </d>
    <a>Margaret Cho</a>
  </q>
  <q id="428">
    <d>Love is the bridge between two hearts.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="429">
    <d>Love is the cheapest of religions.</d>
    <a>Cesare Pavese</a>
  </q>
  <q id="430">
    <d>Love is the child of illusion and the parent of disillusion.</d>
    <a>Miguel de Unamuno</a>
  </q>
  <q id="431">
    <d>Love is the child of illusion and the parent of disillusion.</d>
    <a>Sandy Wilson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="432">
    <d>
      Love is the condition in which the happiness of another person is
      essential to your own.
    </d>
    <a>Robert Heinlein</a>
  </q>
  <q id="433">
    <d>Love is the delightful interval between meeting a beautiful girl and discovering that she looks like a haddock.</d>
    <a>John Barrymore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="434">
    <d>Love is the delusion that one man or woman differs from another.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="435">
    <d>Love is the delusion that one woman differs from another.</d>
    <a>Henry Louis Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="436">
    <d>Love is the direct opposite of hate. By definition it&apos;s something you can&apos;t feel for more than a few minutes at a time, so what&apos;s all this bullshit about loving somebody for the rest of your life?</d>
    <a>Judith Rossner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="437">
    <d>Love is the emblem of eternity; it confounds all notion of time; effaces all memory of a beginning, all fear of an end.</d>
    <a>Germaine De Stael</a>
  </q>
  <q id="438">
    <d>Love is the essential reality and our purpose on earth. To be consciously aware of it, to experience love in ourselves and others, is the meaning of life. Meaning does not lie in things. Meaning lies in us.</d>
    <a>Marianne Williamson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="439">
    <d>Love is the extra effort we make in our dealings with those whom we do not like and once you understand that, you understand all. This idea that love overtakes you is nonsense. This is but a polite manifestation of sex. To love another you have to undertake some fragment of their destiny.</d>
    <a>Quentin Crisp</a>
  </q>
  <q id="440">
    <d>Love is the final end of the world&apos;s history, the Amen of the universe.</d>
    <a>Novalis Hardenberg</a>
  </q>
  <q id="441">
    <d>Love is the flower of life, and blossoms unexpectedly and without law, and must be plucked where it is found, and enjoyed for the brief hour of its duration.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="442">
    <d>Love is the force that transforms and improves the Soul of the World.</d>
    <a>Paulo Coelho</a>
  </q>
  <q id="443">
    <d>Love is the fulfilling of the Law.</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="444">
    <d>Love is the great miracle cure. Loving ourselves works miracles in our lives.</d>
    <a>Louise L. Hay</a>
  </q>
  <q id="445">
    <d>Love is the immortal flow of energy that nourishes, extends and preserves. Its eternal goal is life.</d>
    <a>Smiley Blanton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="446">
    <d>Love is the irresistible desire to be desired irresistibly.</d>
    <a>Louis Ginsberg</a>
  </q>
  <q id="447">
    <d>Love is the joy of the good, the wonder of the wise, the amazement of the Gods.</d>
    <a>Plato</a>
  </q>
  <q id="448">
    <d>Love is the last relay and ultimate outposts of eternity.</d>
    <a>Dante Gabriel Rossetti</a>
  </q>
  <q id="449">
    <d>Love is the magician that pulls man out of his own hat.</d>
    <a>Ben Hecht</a>
  </q>
  <q id="450">
    <d>Love is the master key that opens the gates of happiness.</d>
    <a>Oliver Wendell Holmes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="451">
    <d>Love is the master key which opens the gates of happiness.</d>
    <a>Oliver Wendell Holmes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="452">
    <d>Love is the only bow of life&apos;s dark cloud. It is the Morning and Evening Star. It shines upon the cradle of the babe, and sheds its radiance upon the quiet tomb. It is the Mother of Art, inspirer of poet, patriot, and philosopher. It is the air and light of every heart, builder of every home, kinder of every fire on every hearth, It was the first dream of immortality. It fills the world with melody. Love is the magician, the enchanter, that changes worthless things to joy, and makes right royal kings of common clay.</d>
    <a>Robert G. Ingersoll</a>
  </q>
  <q id="453">
    <d>Love is the only gold.</d>
    <a>Alfred Lord Tennyson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="454">
    <d>Love is the only sane and satisfactory answer to the problem of human existence.</d>
    <a>Erich Fromm</a>
  </q>
  <q id="455">
    <d>Love is the poetry of the senses.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="456">
    <d>Love is the poetry of the senses.</d>
    <a>Honor? de Balzac</a>
  </q>
  <q id="457">
    <d>Love is the river of life in the world.</d>
    <a>Henry Ward Beecher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="458">
    <d>Love is the same as like except you feel sexier.</d>
    <a>Judith Viorst</a>
  </q>
  <q id="459">
    <d>Love is the silent saying and saying of a single name.</d>
    <a>Mignon McLaughlin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="460">
    <d>Love is the strange bewilderment that overtakes one person on account of another person.</d>
    <a>James Thurber</a>
  </q>
  <q id="461">
    <d>Love is the total absence of fear. Love asks no questions. Its natural state is one of extension and expansion, not comparison and measurement.</d>
    <a>Gerald G. Jampolsky</a>
  </q>
  <q id="462">
    <d>Love is the triumph of imagination over intelligence.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="463">
    <d>Love is the triumph of imagination over intelligence.</d>
    <a>Henry Louis Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="464">
    <d>Love is the wild card of existence.</d>
    <a>Rita Mae Brown</a>
  </q>
  <q id="465">
    <d>Love is the wisdom of the fool and the folly of the wise.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="466">
    <d>Love is the word used to label the sexual excitement of the young, the habituation of the middle-aged, and the mutual dependence of the old.</d>
    <a>John Ciardi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="467">
    <d>Love is too young to know what conscience is.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="468">
    <d>Love is what happens to a man and woman who don&apos;t know each other.</d>
    <a>W. Somerset Maugham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="469">
    <d>Love is what is left in a relationship after all the selfishness is taken out.</d>
    <a>Nick Richardson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="470">
    <d>Love is what you&apos;ve been through with somebody.</d>
    <a>James Thurber</a>
  </q>
  <q id="471">
    <d>Love is, above all, the gift of oneself.</d>
    <a>Jean Anouilh Ardele</a>
  </q>
  <q id="472">
    <d>Love just doesn&apos;t just sit there, like a stone, it has to be made like bread, remade all the time, made new.</d>
    <a>Ursula Kroeber Le Guin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="473">
    <d>Love laughs at locksmiths.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="474">
    <d>Love life and life will love you back. Love people and they will love you back.</d>
    <a>Arthur Rubinstein</a>
  </q>
  <q id="475">
    <d>
      Love looks not with the eyes, but with the mind;
      And therefore is winged Cupid painted blind.
    </d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="476">
    <d>Love makes everything that is heavy light.</d>
    <a>Thomas Kempis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="477">
    <d>Love makes the time pass. Time makes love pass.</d>
    <a> Euripides</a>
  </q>
  <q id="478">
    <d>Love makes the wildest spirit tame, and the tamest spirit wild.</d>
    <a>Alexis Delp</a>
  </q>
  <q id="479">
    <d>Love makes your soul crawl out from its hiding place.</d>
    <a>
      Zora Neale Hurston
    </a>
  </q>
  <q id="480">
    <d>Love matches are made by people who are content, for a month of honey, to condemn themselves to a life of vinegar.</d>
    <a>Marguerite Blessington</a>
  </q>
  <q id="481">
    <d>Love may be blind, but it can sure find its way around in the dark!</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="482">
    <d>Love me and the world is mine.</d>
    <a>David Reed</a>
  </q>
  <q id="483">
    <d>Love means never having to say you&apos;re sorry.</d>
    <a>Erich Segal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="484">
    <d>Love means the body, the soul, the life, the entire being. We feel love as we feel the warmth of our blood, we breathe love as we breathe air, we hold it in ourselves as we hold our thoughts. Nothing more exists for us.</d>
    <a>Maupassant</a>
  </q>
  <q id="485">
    <d>Love means to love that which is unlovable; or it is no virtue at all.</d>
    <a>G. K. Chesterton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="486">
    <d>Love must be as much a light, as it is a flame.</d>
    <a>Henry David Thoreau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="487">
    <d>Love never dies a natural death. It dies because we don&apos;t know how to replenish its source. It dies of blindness and errors and betrayals. It dies of illness and wounds; it dies of weariness, of withering, of tarnishing.</d>
    <a>Anais Nin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="488">
    <d>Love never dies a natural death. It dies because we don&apos;t know how to replenish its source. It dies of blindness and errors and betrayals. It dies of illness and wounds; it dies of weariness, of witherings, of tarnishings.</d>
    <a>Anais Nin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="489">
    <d>Love never reasons, but profusely gives; it gives like a thoughtless prodigal its all, and then trembles least it has done to little.</d>
    <a>Hannah More</a>
  </q>
  <q id="490">
    <d>Love one another and you will be happy. It&apos;s as simple and as difficult as that.</d>
    <a>Michael Leunig</a>
  </q>
  <q id="491">
    <d>Love poems are always cliche to me but not to the person it&apos;s for.</d>
    <a>James Dye</a>
  </q>
  <q id="492">
    <d>Love possesses not nor will it be possessed, for love is sufficient unto love.</d>
    <a>Kahlil Gibran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="493">
    <d>Love rules his kingdom without a sword.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="494">
    <d>Love seeketh not itself to please, nor for itself hath any care, but for another gives its ease, and builds a Heaven in Hell&apos;s despair.</d>
    <a>William Blake</a>
  </q>
  <q id="495">
    <d>Love seeks no cause beyond itself and no fruit; it is its own fruit, its own enjoyment. I love because I love; I love in order that I may love.</d>
    <a>St. Bernard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="496">
    <d>Love shall be our token; love be yours and love be mine.</d>
    <a>Christina Rossetti</a>
  </q>
  <q id="497">
    <d>Love sought is good, but given unsought is better.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="498">
    <d>Love takes off masks that we fear we cannot live without and know we cannot live within.</d>
    <a>James Baldwin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="499">
    <d>Love talked about is easily turned aside, but love demonstrated is irresistible.</d>
    <a>Stan Mooneyham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="500">
    <d>Love the art in yourself and not yourself in the art.</d>
    <a>Konstantin Stanislavisky</a>
  </q>
  <q id="501">
    <d>Love the giver more than the gift.</d>
    <a>Brigham Young</a>
  </q>
  <q id="502">
    <d>Love the moment and the energy of the moment will spread beyond all boundaries.</d>
    <a>Sister Corita Kent</a>
  </q>
  <q id="503">
    <d>Love the whole world as a mother lovers her only child.</d>
    <a>Buddha</a>
  </q>
  <q id="504">
    <d>Love thou the rose, yet leave it on its stem.</d>
    <a>Edward George Bulwer-Lytton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="505">
    <d>Love to me is a feeling, to have universal love you have to always feel love no matter what.</d>
    <a>James Dye</a>
  </q>
  <q id="506">
    <d>Love touched her heart, and lo! It beats high, and burns with such brave hearts.</d>
    <a>Richard Crawshaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="507">
    <d>Love was as subtly caught, as a disease; But being got it is a treasure sweet, which to defend is harder than to get: And ought not be profaned on either part, for though &apos;Tis got by chance,  &apos;Tis kept by art.</d>
    <a>John Donne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="508">
    <d>Love wholeheartedly, be surprised, give thanks and praise then you will discover the fullness of your life.</d>
    <a>David Steindl-Rast</a>
  </q>
  <q id="509">
    <d>Love will find a way. Indifference will find an excuse.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="510">
    <d>Love without attachment is light.</d>
    <a>Norman O. Brown</a>
  </q>
  <q id="511">
    <d>Love works a different way in different minds, the fool it enlightens and the wise it blinds.</d>
    <a>John Dryden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="512">
    <d>Love works in miracles every day: such as weakening the strong, and stretching the weak; making fools of the wise, and wise men of fools; favouring the passions, destroying reason, and in a word, turning everything topsy-turvy.</d>
    <a>Marguerite de Valois</a>
  </q>
  <q id="513">
    <d>Love, all alike, no season knows, nor clime, nor hours, days, months, which are the rags of time.</d>
    <a>John Donne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="514">
    <d>Love, and do what thou wilt: whether thou hold thy peace, through love hold thy peace; whether thou cry out, through love cry out; whether thou correct, through love correct; whether thou spare, through love do thou spare: let the root of love be within, of this root can nothing spring but what is good.</d>
    <a>Saint Augustine of Hippo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="515">
    <d>Love, Arthur, is a poodle&apos;s chance of attaining the infinite, and personally I have my pride.</d>
    <a>Louis-Ferdinand Celine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="516">
    <d>Love, by its very nature, is unworldly, and it is for this reason rather than its rarity that it is not only apolitical but anti-political, perhaps the most powerful of all anti-political human forces.</d>
    <a>Hannah Arendt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="517">
    <d>Love, I find, is like singing. Everybody can do enough to satisfy themselves, though it may not impress the neighbors as being very much.</d>
    <a>Zora Neale Hurston</a>
  </q>
  <q id="518">
    <d>Love, love, love - all the wretched cant of it, masking egotism, lust, masochism, fantasy under a mythology of sentimental postures, a welter of self-induced miseries and joys, blinding and masking the essential personalities in the frozen gestures of courtship, in the kissing and the dating and the desire, the compliments and the quarrels which vivify its barrenness.</d>
    <a>Germaine Greer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="519">
    <d>LOVE, the feeling, is the fruit of LOVE, the verb.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="520">
    <d>Love, while you are able to love.</d>
    <a>A. Frieligrath</a>
  </q>
  <q id="521">
    <d>Love, you are eternal like springtime.</d>
    <a>Juan Ramon Jiminez</a>
  </q>
  <q id="522">
    <d>Love, you know, seeks to make happy rather than to be happy.</d>
    <a>Ralph Connor</a>
  </q>
  <q id="523">
    <d>Love... Force it and it disappears. You cannot will love, nor even control it. You can only guide its expression. It comes or it goes according to those qualities in life that invite it or deny its presence.</d>
    <a>David Seabury</a>
  </q>
  <q id="524">
    <d>Lovers are fools, but Nature makes them so.</d>
    <a>Elbert Hubbard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="525">
    <d>Lovers may be - and indeed generally are - enemies, but they never can be friends, because there must always be a spice of jealousy and a something of Self in all their speculations.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="526">
    <d>Lovers may be - and indeed generally are - enemies, but they never can be friends, because there must always be a spice of jealousy and a something of Self in all their speculations.</d>
    <a>Lord Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="527">
    <d>Lovers should also have their days off.</d>
    <a>Natalie Clifford Barney</a>
  </q>
  <q id="528">
    <d>Lovers who love truly do not write down their happiness.</d>
    <a>Anatole France</a>
  </q>
  <q id="529">
    <d>Love&apos;s greatest gift is its ability to make everything it touches sacred.</d>
    <a>Barbara De Angelis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="530">
    <d>Love&apos;s overbrimming mystery joins death and life. It has filled my cup of pain with joy.</d>
    <a>Rabindranath Tagore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="531">
    <d>Loving can cost a lot but not loving always costs more, and those who fear to love often find that want of love is an emptiness that robs the joy from life.</d>
    <a>Merle Shan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="532">
    <d>Loving is never a waste of time.</d>
    <a>Astrid Alauda</a>
  </q>
  <q id="533">
    <d>Loving people live in a loving world. Hostile people live in a hostile world. Same world.</d>
    <a>Wayne Dyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="534">
    <d>Madame, it is an old word and each one takes it new and wears it out himself. It is a word that fills with meaning as a bladder with air and the meaning goes out of it as quickly. It may be punctured as a bladder is punctured and patched and blown up again and if you have not had it does not exist for you. All people talk of it, but those who have had it are marked by it, and I would not wish to speak of it further since of all things it is the most ridiculous to talk of and only fools go through it many times.</d>
    <a>Ernest Hemingway</a>
  </q>
  <q id="535">
    <d>Man&apos;s love is of man&apos;s life a part; it is a woman&apos;s whole existence. In her first passion, a woman loves her lover, in all the others all she loves is love.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="536">
    <d>Many a man has fallen in love with a girl in light so dim he would not have chosen a suit by it.</d>
    <a>Maurice Chevalier</a>
  </q>
  <q id="537">
    <d>Many people when they fall in love look for a little haven of refuge from the world, where they can be sure of being admired when they are not admirable, and praised when they are not praiseworthy.</d>
    <a>Bertrand Russell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="538">
    <d>Many will detest you if you spend all your love on yourself.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="539">
    <d>Men and women are not free to love decently until they have analyzed themselves completely and swept away every mystery from sex; and this means the acquisition of a profound philosophical theory based on wide reading of anthropology and enlightened practice.</d>
    <a>Aleister Crowley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="540">
    <d>Mistresses are like books; if you pore upon them too much, they doze you and make you unfit for company; but if used discreetly, you are the fitter for conversation by em.</d>
    <a>William Wycherley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="541">
    <d>Most people would rather give than get affection.</d>
    <a>Aristotle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="542">
    <d>My first thoughts are that I should not let people down, that I should support them and love them.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="543">
    <d>My God, these folks don&apos;t know how to love - that&apos;s why they love so easily.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="544">
    <d>My life is an indivisible whole, and all my attitudes run into one another; and they all have their rise in my insatiable love for mankind.</d>
    <a>Mahatma Gandhi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="545">
    <d>My most brilliant achievement was my ability to be able to persuade my wife to marry me.</d>
    <a>Winston Churchill</a>
  </q>
  <q id="546">
    <d>My tears of love are a waste of time if I turn away</d>
    <a>Kim Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="547">
    <d>My wife heard me say I love you a thousand times, but she never once heard me say sorry</d>
    <a>Bruce Willis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="548">
    <d>Naturally, love&apos;s the most distant possibility.</d>
    <a>Georges Bataille</a>
  </q>
  <q id="549">
    <d>Never pretend to a love which you do not actually feel, for love is not ours to command. </d>
    <a>Alan Watts</a>
  </q>
  <q id="550">
    <d>Never the time and the place and the loved one all together!</d>
    <a>Robert Browning</a>
  </q>
  <q id="551">
    <d>Never try to define love. Once defined love is confined. Once confined - It dies.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="552">
    <d>No cord nor cable can so forcibly draw, or hold so fast, as love can do with a twined thread.</d>
    <a>Robert Burton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="553">
    <d>No cord or cable can draw so forcibly, or bind so fast, as love can do with a single thread.</d>
    <a>Robert Burton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="554">
    <d>No love is entirely without worth, even when the frivolous calls to the frivolous and the base to the base.</d>
    <a>Iris Murdoch</a>
  </q>
  <q id="555">
    <d>No one has ever loved anyone the way everyone wants to be loved.</d>
    <a>Mignon McLaughlin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="556">
    <d>No one worth possessing can be quite possessed.</d>
    <a>Sara Teasdale</a>
  </q>
  <q id="557">
    <d>No thoughtful man ever came to the end of his life, and had time and a little space of calm from which to look back upon it, who did not know and acknowledge that it was what he had done unselfishly and for others, and nothing else, that satisfied him in the retrospect, and made him feel that he had played the man.</d>
    <a>Woodrow Wilson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="558">
    <d>No three words have greater power than I Love You.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="559">
    <d>No woman marries for money; they are all clever enough, before marrying a millionaire, to fall in love with him first.</d>
    <a>Cesare Pavese</a>
  </q>
  <q id="560">
    <d>Nobody can teach you love. Love you have to find yourself, within your being, by raising your consciousness to higher levels. And when love comes, there is no question of responsibility. You do things because you enjoy doing them for the person you love. You are not obliging the person, you are not even wanting anything in return, not even gratitude. On the contrary, you are grateful that the person has allowed you to do something for him. It was your joy, sheer joy. Love knows nothing of responsibility. It does many things, it is very creative; it shares all that it has, but it is not a responsibility, remember. Responsibility is an ugly word in comparison to love. Love is natural. Responsibility is created by the cunning priests, politicians who want to dominate you in the name of God, in the name of the nation, in the name of family, in the name of religion - any fiction will do. But they don&apos;t talk about love. On the contrary, they are all against love, because love is unable to be controlled by them. A man of love acts out of his own heart, not according to any moral code. A man of love will not join the army because it is his responsibility to fight for his nation. A man of love will say there are no nations, and there is no question of any fight.</d>
    <a>Osho [Chandra Mohan Jain]</a>
  </q>
  <q id="561">
    <d>Not all of us have to possess earthshaking talent. Just common sense and love will do.</d>
    <a>Myrtle Auvil</a>
  </q>
  <q id="562">
    <d>Not to believe in love is a great sign of dullness. There are some people so indirect and lumbering that they think all real affection must rest on circumstantial evidence.</d>
    <a>George Santayana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="563">
    <d>Nothing is impossible for pure love.</d>
    <a>Mahatma Gandhi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="564">
    <d>Nothing is more beautiful than the love that has weathered the storms of life. The love of the young for the young, that is the beginning of life. But the love of the old for the old, that is the beginning of things longer.</d>
    <a>Jerome K. Jerome</a>
  </q>
  <q id="565">
    <d>Nothing takes the taste out of peanut butter quite like unrequited love.</d>
    <a>Charles Monroe Schulz</a>
  </q>
  <q id="566">
    <d>Nowadays men cannot love seven night but they must have all their desires: that love may not endure by reason; for where they be soon accorded and hasty, heat soon it cooleth. Right so fareth love nowadays, soon hot soon cold: this is no stability. But the old love was not so.</d>
    <a>Sir Thomas Malory</a>
  </q>
  <q id="567">
    <d>Nunc scio quit sit amor.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="568">
    <d>Nuptial love makes mankind; friendly love perfects it; but wanton love corrupts and debases it.</d>
    <a>Francis Bacon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="569">
    <d>O Romeo, Romeo! wherefore art thou Romeo?  Deny thy father and refuse thy name; Or, if thou wilt not, be but sworn my love... &apos;Tis but thy name that is my enemy;What&apos;s in a name? that which we call a rose By any other name would smell as sweet...</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="570">
    <d>Oh love will make a dog howl in rhyme.</d>
    <a>John Fletcher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="571">
    <d>Oh, Jacques, we&apos;re used to each other, we&apos;re a pair of captive hawks caught in the same cage, and so we&apos;ve grown used to each other. That&apos;s what passes for love at this dim, shadowy end of the Camino Real.</d>
    <a>Tennessee (Thomas Lanier) Williams</a>
  </q>
  <q id="572">
    <d>Oh, love is real enough; you will find it someday, but it has one archenemy - and that is life.</d>
    <a>Jean Anouilh Ardele</a>
  </q>
  <q id="573">
    <d>On the last analysis, then, love is life. Love never faileth and life never faileth so long as there is love.</d>
    <a>Henry Drummond</a>
  </q>
  <q id="574">
    <d>Once a women has given you her heart you can never get rid of the rest of her.</d>
    <a>Sir John Vanbrugh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="575">
    <d>Once when I was young and true, Someone left me sad- Broke my brittle heart in two; And that was very bad. Love is for unlucky folk. Love is but a curse. Once there was a heart I broke; And that, I think, is worse.</d>
    <a>Dorothy Parker</a>
  </q>
  <q id="576">
    <d>Once you have learned to love, You will have learned to live.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="577">
    <d>One can be a soldier without dying, and a lover without sighing.</d>
    <a>Sir Edwin Arnold</a>
  </q>
  <q id="578">
    <d>One does not fall in love; one grows into love, and love grows in him.</d>
    <a>Karl Menninger</a>
  </q>
  <q id="579">
    <d>
      One heartbreak is like a thousand lessons.
      Loving again is learning them.
    </d>
    <a>Sandra McKendry</a>
  </q>
  <q id="580">
    <d>One is loved because one is loved. No reason is needed for loving.</d>
    <a>Paulo Coelho</a>
  </q>
  <q id="581">
    <d>One seeks to make the loved one entirely happy, or, if that cannot be, entirely wretched.</d>
    <a>Jean De La Bruyere</a>
  </q>
  <q id="582">
    <d>One should always be in love. That is the reason one should never marry.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="583">
    <d>One should never direct people towards happiness, because happiness too is an idol of the market-place. One should direct them towards mutual affection. A beast gnawing at its prey can be happy too, but only human beings can feel affection for each other, and this is the highest achievement they can aspire to.</d>
    <a>Alexandr Solzhenitsyn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="584">
    <d>One who has not only the four S&apos;s, which are required in every good lover, but even the whole alphabet; as for example... Agreeable, Bountiful, Constant, Dutiful, Easy, Faithful, Gallant, Honorable, Ingenious, Kind, Loyal, Mild, Noble, Officious, Prudent, Quiet, Rich, Secret, True, Valiant, Wise; the X indeed, is too harsh a letter to agree with him, but he is Young and Zealous.</d>
    <a>Miguel de Cervantes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="585">
    <d>
      One word frees us of all the weight and pain in life.
      That word is Love.
    </d>
    <a> Sophocles</a>
  </q>
  <q id="586">
    <d>One word frees us of all the weight and pain of life; that word is love.</d>
    <a>Sophocles</a>
  </q>
  <q id="587">
    <d>One would always want to think of oneself as being on the side of love, ready to recognize it and wish it well -but, when confronted with it in others, one so often resented it, questioned its true nature, secretly dismissed the particular instance as folly or promiscuity. Was it merely jealousy, or a reluctance to admit so noble and enviable a sentiment in anyone but oneself?</d>
    <a>Shirley Hazzard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="588">
    <d>Only from the heart Can you touch the sky.</d>
    <a>Rumi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="589">
    <d>Only the really plain people know about love -the very fascinating ones try so hard to create an impression that they very soon exhaust their talents.</d>
    <a>Katharine Hepburn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="590">
    <d>Only the words of love kept alive are worthy of not being wasted</d>
    <a>Arlo Guthrie</a>
  </q>
  <q id="591">
    <d>Our affections as well as our bodies are in perpetual flux.</d>
    <a>Jean Jacques Rousseau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="592">
    <d>Paradise is always where love dwells.</d>
    <a>Jean Paul F. Richter</a>
  </q>
  <q id="593">
    <d>Paradoxically, we fail to disclose ourselves to other people because we want so much to be loved. Because we feel that way we present ourselves as someone we think can be loved and accepted, and we conceal whatever would mar that image. Another reason we hide is to protect ourselves from change. . . Still another reason we don&apos;t disclose ourselves is that we were never taught how. . . Personal ambitions and economic pressures also give us powerful reasons for concealing what we really are. . . All of us hide behind the iron curtain of our public selves. . . Men hide what prevents them from seeming strong and masculine. . . Disclosure is so important (because) without it we really cannot know ourselves. Or to put it another way, we learn to deceive ourselves while we are trying to deceive others. For example, if I never express my sorrow, my love, my joy, I&apos;ll smother those feelings in myself until I almost forget they were once part of me.</d>
    <a>Sidney Jourard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="594">
    <d>Parrots, tortoises and redwoods live a longer life than men do; Men a longer life than dogs do; Dogs a longer life than love does.</d>
    <a>Edna St. Vincent Millay</a>
  </q>
  <q id="595">
    <d>People love others not for who they are, but for how they make them feel.</d>
    <a>Irwin Federman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="596">
    <d>People need loving the most when they deserve it the least.</d>
    <a>John Harrigan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="597">
    <d>People who are not in love fail to understand how an intelligent man can suffer because of a very ordinary woman. This is like being surprised that anyone should be stricken with cholera because of a creature so insignificant as the comma bacillus.</d>
    <a>Marcel Proust</a>
  </q>
  <q id="598">
    <d>People who are sensible about love are incapable of it.</d>
    <a>Douglas Yates</a>
  </q>
  <q id="599">
    <d>Perfect love is rare indeed - for to be a lover will require that you continually have the subtlety of the very wise, the flexibility of the child, the sensitivity of the artist, the understanding of the philosopher, the acceptance of the saint, the tolerance of the scholar and the fortitude of the certain.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="600">
    <d>Perhaps the most important reason for self-disclosure is that without it we cannot truly love.</d>
    <a>Sidney Jourard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="601">
    <d>Perhaps the old monks were right when they tried to root love out; perhaps the poets are right when they try to water it. It is a blood-red flower, with the color of sin; but there is always the scent of a god about it.</d>
    <a>Olive Schreiner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="602">
    <d>Pity the selfishness of lovers: it is brief, a forlorn hope; it is impossible.</d>
    <a>Elizabeth Bowen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="603">
    <d>Pure love is a willingness to give without a thought of receiving anything in return.</d>
    <a>Peace Pilgrim</a>
  </q>
  <q id="604">
    <d>Queen Guenever, for whom I make here a little mention, that while she lived she was a true lover, and therefore she had a good end.</d>
    <a>Sir Thomas Malory</a>
  </q>
  <q id="605">
    <d>Real love is a pilgrimage. It happens when there is no strategy, but it is very rare because most people are strategists.</d>
    <a>Anita Brookner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="606">
    <d>Real love stories never have endings.</d>
    <a>Richard Bach</a>
  </q>
  <q id="607">
    <d>Relationships - of all kinds - are like sand held in your hand. Held loosely, with an open hand, the sand remains where it is. The minute you close your hand and squeeze tightly to hold on, the sand trickles through your fingers. You may hold onto some of it, but most will be spilled. A relationship is like that. Held loosely, with respect and freedom for the other person, it is likely to remain intact. But hold too tightly, too possessively, and the relationship slips away and is lost.</d>
    <a>Kaleel Jamison</a>
  </q>
  <q id="608">
    <d>Religion it self is nothing else but Love to God and Man.He that lives in Love lives in God, says the Beloved Disciple: And to be sure a Man can live no where better.  It is most reasonable Men should value that Benefit, which is most durable. Now Tongues shall cease, and Prophecy fail, and Faith shall be consummated in Sight, and Hope in Enjoyment; but Love remains.Love is indeed Heaven upon Earth; since Heaven above would not be Heaven without it: For where there is not Love; there is Fear: But perfect Love casts out Fear. And yet we naturally fear most to offend what we most Love. What we Love, we</d>
    <a>William Penn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="609">
    <d>Romantic love is an illusion. Most of us discover this truth at the end of a love affair or else when the sweet emotions of love lead us into marriage and then turn down their flames.</d>
    <a>Thomas Moore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="610">
    <d>Romantic love, in pornography as in life, is the mythic celebration of female negation. For a woman, love is defined as her willingness to submit to her own annihilation. The proof of love is that she is willing to be destroyed by the one whom she loves, for his sake. For the woman, love is always self-sacrifice, the sacrifice of identity, will, and bodily integrity, in order to fulfill and redeem the masculinity of her lover.</d>
    <a>Andrea Dworkin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="611">
    <d>Sex alleviates tension. Love causes it.</d>
    <a>Woody Allen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="612">
    <d>Someday, after mastering winds, waves, tides and gravity, we shall harness the energy of love; and for the second time in the history of the world, man will have discovered fire.</d>
    <a>Pierre Teilhard de Chardin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="613">
    <d>Sometimes the heart sees what is invisible to the eye.</d>
    <a>H. Jackson Brown, Jr.</a>
  </q>
  <q id="614">
    <d>Sometimes, when one person is missing, the whole world seems depopulated.</d>
    <a>Alphonse De Lamartine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="615">
    <d>Son, I&apos;d say you were going at it the wrong end first, said the Judge, turning up his coat-collar. How could you care about one girl? Have you ever cared about one leaf?Riley, listening to the wildcat with an itchy hunter&apos;s look, snatched at the leaves blowing about us like midnight butterflies; alive, fluttering as though to escape and fly, one stayed trapped between his fingers. The Judge, too: he caught a leaf; and it was worth more in his hand than in Riley&apos;s. Pressing it mildly against his cheek, he distantly said, We are speaking of love. A leaf, a handful of seed-begin with these, learn a little what it is to love. First, a leaf, a fall of rain, then someone to receive what a leaf has taught you, what a fall of rain has ripened. No easy process, understand; it could take a lifetime, it has mine, and still I&apos;ve never mastered it-I only know how true it is: that love is a chain of love, as nature is a chain of life.</d>
    <a>Truman Capote</a>
  </q>
  <q id="616">
    <d>Soul meets soul on lover&apos;s lips.</d>
    <a>Percy Bysshe Shelly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="617">
    <d>Speak low if you speak love.</d>
    <a>Don Pedro</a>
  </q>
  <q id="618">
    <d>Stay me with flagons, comfort me with apples: for I am sick of love. The Song Of Solomon 2:5</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="619">
    <d>Subdue your passion or it will subdue you.</d>
    <a>Horace</a>
  </q>
  <q id="620">
    <d>Suddenly the ground seemed to give way beneath me,and I found myself in quite another region.Within five minutes I went throughsome such reflections as the following:the loneliness of the human soul is unendurable;nothing can penetrate it except the highest intensityof the sort of love that religious teachers have preached;whatever does not spring from this motive is harmful,or at best useless;it follows that war is wrong,that a public school education is abominable,that the use of force is to be deprecated,and that in human relations one should penetrateto the core of loneliness in each person and speak to that.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="621">
    <d>Sympathy constitutes friendship; but in love there is a sort of antipathy, or opposing passion. Each strives to be the other, and both together make up one whole.</d>
    <a>Samuel Taylor Coleridge</a>
  </q>
  <q id="622">
    <d>Talk not of wasted affection; affection never was wasted.</d>
    <a>Henry Wadsworth Longfellow</a>
  </q>
  <q id="623">
    <d>Tell me who admires you and loves you, and I will tell you who you are.</d>
    <a>Charles Augustin Sainte-Beuve</a>
  </q>
  <q id="624">
    <d>That is the true season of love; when we believe that we alone can love, that no one could ever have loved as much before, and that no one will ever love in the same way again.</d>
    <a>Johann von Goethe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="625">
    <d>The advantage of love at first sight is that it delays a second sight.</d>
    <a>Natalie Clifford Barney</a>
  </q>
  <q id="626">
    <d>The affections are like lightning: you cannot tell where they will strike till they have fallen.</d>
    <a>Jean Baptiste Lacordaire</a>
  </q>
  <q id="627">
    <d>The art of love ... is largely the art of persistence.</d>
    <a>Albert Ellis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="628">
    <d>
      The best and most beautiful things in this world cannot be seen or
      even heard, but must be felt with the heart.
    </d>
    <a>Helen Keller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="629">
    <d>
      The best and most beautiful things in this world cannot be seen or
      even heard, but must be felt with the heart.
    </d>
    <a>Helen Keller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="630">
    <d>The best proof of love is trust.</d>
    <a>Joyce Brothers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="631">
    <d>The best way to know God is to love many things.</d>
    <a>Vincent Van Gogh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="632">
    <d>The best way will be to avoid each other without appearing to do so - or if we jostle, at any rate not to bite.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="633">
    <d>The bottom line is that (a) people are never perfect, but love can be, (b) that is the one and only way that the mediocre and vile can be transformed, and (c) doing that makes it that. We waste time looking for the perfect lover, instead of creating the perfect love.</d>
    <a>Tom Robbins</a>
  </q>
  <q id="634">
    <d>The chemist who can extract from his heart&apos;s elements, compassion, respect, longing, patience, regret, surprise, and forgiveness and compound them into one can create that atom which is called love.</d>
    <a>Kahlil Gibran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="635">
    <d>The choicest thing this world has for a man is affection.</d>
    <a>Josiah Gilbert Holland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="636">
    <d>The commandment is that you shall love, but when you understand life and yourself, then it is as if you should not need to be commanded, because to love human beings is still the only thing worth living for; without this life you really do not live.</d>
    <a>Soren Kierkegaard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="637">
    <d>The cure for all ills and wrongs, the cares, the sorrows and the crimes of humanity, all lie in the one word &apos;love.&apos; It is the divine vitality that everywhere produces and restores life.</d>
    <a>Lydia Maria Child</a>
  </q>
  <q id="638">
    <d>The desire for possession is insatiable, to such a point that it can survive even love itself. To love, therefore, is to sterilize the person one loves.</d>
    <a>Albert Camus</a>
  </q>
  <q id="639">
    <d>The enthusiasm of a woman&apos;s love is even beyond the biographer&apos;s. </d>
    <a>Jane Austen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="640">
    <d>The fate of love is that it always seems too little or too much.</d>
    <a>Amelia E. Barr</a>
  </q>
  <q id="641">
    <d>The female that loves unrequited sleeps, And the male that loves unrequited sleeps, The head of the money-maker that plotted all day sleeps, And the enraged and treacherous dispositions, all, all sleep.</d>
    <a>Walt Whitman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="642">
    <d>The fickleness of the women I love is only equaled by the infernal constancy of the women who love me.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="643">
    <d>The greatest gift that you can give to others is the gift of unconditional love and acceptance.</d>
    <a>Brian Tracy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="644">
    <d>The greatest happiness of life is the conviction that we are loved - loved for ourselves, or rather, loved in spite of ourselves.</d>
    <a>Victor Hugo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="645">
    <d>The greatest healing therapy is friendship and love.</d>
    <a>Hubert Humprey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="646">
    <d>The greatest weakness of most humans is their hesitancy to tell others how much they love them while they&apos;re still alive.</d>
    <a>Orlando A. Battista</a>
  </q>
  <q id="647">
    <d>The hardest of all is learning to be a well of affection, and not a fountain; to show them we love them not when we feel like it, but when they do.</d>
    <a>Nan Fairbrother</a>
  </q>
  <q id="648">
    <d>The heart has its reasons that reason knows nothing of.</d>
    <a>Blaise Pascal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="649">
    <d>The hours I spend with you I look upon as sort of a perfumed garden, a dim twilight, and a fountain singing to it... you and you alone make me feel that I am alive. Other men it is said have seen angels, but I have seen thee and thou art enough.</d>
    <a>George Moore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="650">
    <d>The hunger for love is much more difficult to remove than the hunger for bread.</d>
    <a>Mother Theresa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="651">
    <d>The idea that nations should love one another, or that business concerns or marketing boards should love one another, or that a man in Portugal should love a man in Peru of whom he has never heard -it is absurd, unreal, dangerous. The fact is we can only love what we know personally. And we cannot know much.</d>
    <a>E. M. Forster</a>
  </q>
  <q id="652">
    <d>The Impossible Generalized Man today is the critic who believes in loving those unworthy of love as well as those worthy -yet believes this only insofar as no personal risk is entailed. Meaning he loves no one, worthy or no. This is what makes him impossible.</d>
    <a>Nelson Algren</a>
  </q>
  <q id="653">
    <d>The life and love we create is the life and love we live.</d>
    <a>Leo Buscaglia</a>
  </q>
  <q id="654">
    <d>The love boat has crashed against the everyday.</d>
    <a>Vladimir Mayakovsky</a>
  </q>
  <q id="655">
    <d>The love of liberty is the love of others; the love of power is the love of ourselves. We cannot force love.</d>
    <a>William Hazlitt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="656">
    <d>The love we give away is the only love we keep.</d>
    <a>Elbert Hubbard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="657">
    <d>The lover knows much more about absolute good and universal beauty than any logician or theologian, unless the latter, too, be lovers in disguise.</d>
    <a>George Santayana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="658">
    <d>The lover of life makes the whole world into his family, just as the lover of the fair sex creates his from all the lovely women he has found, from those that could be found, and those who are impossible to find.</d>
    <a>Charles Baudelaire</a>
  </q>
  <q id="659">
    <d>The magic of first love is our ignorance that it can never end.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Disraeli</a>
  </q>
  <q id="660">
    <d>The man who has never made a fool of himself in love will never be wise in love.</d>
    <a>Theodor Reik</a>
  </q>
  <q id="661">
    <d>The minute I heard my first love story I started looking for you, not knowing how blind that was. Lovers don&apos;t finally meet somewhere. They&apos;re in each other all along.</d>
    <a>Rumi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="662">
    <d>The moment we indulge our affections, the earth is metamorphosed, there is no winter and no night; all tragedies, all ennui s, vanish, all duties even.</d>
    <a>Ralph Waldo Emerson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="663">
    <d>The moment you have in your heart this extraordinary thing called love and feel the depth, the delight, the ecstasy of it, you will discover that for you the world is transformed.</d>
    <a>J. Krishnamurti</a>
  </q>
  <q id="664">
    <d>The more connections you and your lover make, not just between your bodies, but between your minds, your hearts, and your souls, the more you will strengthen the fabric of your relationship, and the more real moments you will experience together.</d>
    <a>Barbara De Angelis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="665">
    <d>The more familiar two people become, the more the language they speak together departs from that of the ordinary, dictionary-defined discourse. Familiarity creates a new language, an in-house language of intimacy that carries reference to the story the two lovers are weaving together and that cannot be readily understood by others.</d>
    <a>Alain de Botton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="666">
    <d>The most important thing a father can do for his children is to love their mother.</d>
    <a>Theodore M. Hesburgh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="667">
    <d>The motto of chivalry is also the motto of wisdom; to serve all, but love only one.</d>
    <a>Honore de Balzac</a>
  </q>
  <q id="668">
    <d>The one who loves least controls the relationship.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="669">
    <d>The only abnormality is the incapacity to love.</d>
    <a>Anais Nin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="670">
    <d>The only thing bigger than God`s great universe is man`s ego.</d>
    <a>Gary Sevakis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="671">
    <d>The only victory over love is flight.</d>
    <a>Napoleon Bonaparte</a>
  </q>
  <q id="672">
    <d>The opposite of love is not to hate but to separate. If love and hate have something in common it is because, in both cases, their energy is that of bringing and holding together</d>
    <a>John Berger</a>
  </q>
  <q id="673">
    <d>The pleasures of love are pains that become desirable, where sweetness and torment blend, and so love is voluntary insanity, infernal paradise, and celestial hell - in short, harmony of opposite yearnings, sorrowful laughter, soft diamond.</d>
    <a>Umberto Eco</a>
  </q>
  <q id="674">
    <d>The power of love, as the basis of a State, has never been tried.</d>
    <a>Ralph Waldo Emerson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="675">
    <d>The richest love is that which submits to the arbitration of time.</d>
    <a>Lawrence Durrell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="676">
    <d>The root of the matter the thing I mean is love, Christian love, or compassion. If you feel this, you have a motive for existence, a guide for action, a reason for courage, an imperative necessity for intellectual honesty.</d>
    <a>Bertrand Russell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="677">
    <d>The rose speaks of love silently, in a language known only to the heart.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="678">
    <d>The season of love is the carnival of egoism and it brings a touchstone to our natures.</d>
    <a>George Meredith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="679">
    <d>The Solitary answered: Such a Form Full well I recollect. We often crossed Each other&apos;s path; but, as the Intruder seemed Fondly to prize the silence which he kept, And I as willingly did cherish mine, We met, and passed, like shadows. I have heard, From my good Host, that being crazed in brain By unrequited love, he scaled the rocks, Dived into caves, and pierced the matted woods,In hope to find some virtuous herb of power To cure his malady!</d>
    <a>William Wordsworth</a>
  </q>
  <q id="680">
    <d>The spiritualization of sensuality is called love: it is a great triumph over Christianity.</d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="681">
    <d>The story of love is not important - what is important is that one is capable of love. It is perhaps the only glimpse we are permitted of eternity.</d>
    <a>Helen Hayes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="682">
    <d>The supreme happiness in life is the conviction that we are loved - loved for ourselves, or rather, loved in spite of ourselves.</d>
    <a>Victor Hugo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="683">
    <d>The sweetest joy, the wildest woe is love.</d>
    <a>Pearl Bailey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="684">
    <d>The true beloveds of this world are in their lover&apos;s eyes lilacs opening, ship lights, school bells, a landscape, remembered conversations, friends, a child&apos;s Sunday, lost voices, one&apos;s favorite suit, autumn and all seasons, memory, yes, it being the earth and water of existence, memory.</d>
    <a>Truman Capote</a>
  </q>
  <q id="685">
    <d>The value of love will always be stronger than the value of hate.. Any nation or group of nations which employs hatred eventually is torn to pieces by hatred...</d>
    <a>Franklin D. Roosevelt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="686">
    <d>The way is not in the sky. The way is in the heart.</d>
    <a>Buddha</a>
  </q>
  <q id="687">
    <d>The way of peace is the way of love. Love is the greatest power on earth. It conquers all things.</d>
    <a>Peace Pilgrim</a>
  </q>
  <q id="688">
    <d>The way to love anything is to realize that it might be lost.</d>
    <a>G. K. Chesterton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="689">
    <d>The way to love anything is to realize that it might be lost.</d>
    <a>Gilbert Keith Chesterton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="690">
    <d>The weight of the world is love. Under the burden of solitude, under the burden of dissatisfaction.</d>
    <a>Allen Ginsberg</a>
  </q>
  <q id="691">
    <d>The world is wonderful and beautiful and good beyond one&apos;s wildest imagination. Never, never, never could one conceive what love is, beforehand, never. Life can be great -quite god-like. It can be so. God be thanked I have proved it.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="692">
    <d>Then, wearied by the uncertainty and difficulties with which each scheme appeared to be attended, he bent up his mind to the strong effort of shaking off his love, like dew-drops from the lion&apos;s mane, and resuming those studies and that career of life which his unrequited affection had so long and so fruitlessly interrupted. In this last resolution he endeavoured to fortify himself by every argument which pride, as well as reason, could suggest.</d>
    <a>Sir Walter Scott</a>
  </q>
  <q id="693">
    <d>There are no guarantees. From the viewpoint of fear, none are strong enough. From the viewpoint of love, none are necessary.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="694">
    <d>There exists, between people in love, a kind of capital held by each. This is not just a stock of affects or pleasure, but also the possibility of playing double or quits with the share you hold in the other&apos;s heart.</d>
    <a>Jean Baudrillard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="695">
    <d>There is a law that man should love his neighbor as himself. In a few hundred years it should be as natural to mankind as breathing or the upright gait; but if he does not learn it he must perish.</d>
    <a>Alfred Adler</a>
  </q>
  <q id="696">
    <d>There is always some madness in love. But there is also always some reason in madness.</d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="697">
    <d>There is always something left to love. And if you ain&apos;t learned that, you ain&apos;t learned nothing. Have you cried for that boy today? I don&apos;t mean for yourself and for the family &apos;cause we lost the money. I mean for him; what he&apos;s been through and what it done to him. Child, when do you think is the time to love somebody the most; when they done good and made things easy for everybody? Well then, you ain&apos;t through learning - because that ain&apos;t the time at all. It&apos;s when he&apos;s at his lowest and can&apos;t believe in hisself &apos;cause the world done whipped him so. When you starts measuring somebody, measure him right child, measure him right. Make sure you done taken into account what hills and valleys he come through before he got to wherever he is.</d>
    <a>Lorraine Hansberry</a>
  </q>
  <q id="698">
    <d>There is an important difference between love and friendship. While the former delights in extremes and opposites, the latter demands equality.</d>
    <a>Madame de Maintenon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="699">
    <d>There is no disguise which can hide love for long where it exists, or simulate it where it does not.</d>
    <a>Fran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="700">
    <d>There is no disguise which can hide love for long where it exists, or simulate it where it does not.</d>
    <a>La Rochefoucauld</a>
  </q>
  <q id="701">
    <d>There is no fear in love; but perfect love casts out fear.</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="702">
    <d>There is no living with thee, nor without thee.</d>
    <a>Marcus Valerius Martial</a>
  </q>
  <q id="703">
    <d>There is no pain equal to that which two lovers can inflict on one another. This should be made clear to all who contemplate such a union. The avoidance of this pain is the beginning of wisdom, for it is strong enough to contaminate the rest of our lives.</d>
    <a>Cyril Connolly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="704">
    <d>There is no remedy for love than to love more.</d>
    <a>Henry David Thoreau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="705">
    <d>There is no surprise more magical than the surprise of being loved. It is God&apos;s finger on man&apos;s shoulder.</d>
    <a>Charles Morgan</a>
  </q>
  <q id="706">
    <d>There is only one happiness in life: to love and be loved.</d>
    <a>George Sand</a>
  </q>
  <q id="707">
    <d>There is only one terminal dignity - love.</d>
    <a>Helen Hayes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="708">
    <d>There&apos;s no good story without romance.</d>
    <a>Stephenie Meyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="709">
    <d>There&apos;s nothing in the world like the devotion of a married woman. It&apos;s a thing no married man knows anything about.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="710">
    <d>These two imparadised in one another&apos;s arms, the happier Eden, shall enjoy their fill of bliss on bliss.</d>
    <a>John Milton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="711">
    <d>They do not love that do not show their love. The course of true love never did run smooth. Love is a familiar. Love is a devil. There is no evil angel but Love.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="712">
    <d>Think about a woman. Doesn&apos;t know you&apos;re thinking about her. Doesn&apos;t care you&apos;re thinking about her. Makes you think about her even more. </d>
    <a>Martin Sage and Sybil Adelman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="713">
    <d>This is my commandment, that ye love one another. Jesus, In John 15:12</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="714">
    <d>This is the miracle that happens every time to those who really love; the more they give, the more they possess.</d>
    <a>Rainer Maria Rilke</a>
  </q>
  <q id="715">
    <d>This was love at first sight, love everlasting: a feeling unknown, unhoped for, unexpected - in so far as it could be a matter of conscious awareness; it took entire possession of him, and he understood, with joyous amazement, that this was for life.</d>
    <a>Thomas Mann</a>
  </q>
  <q id="716">
    <d>This world is full of beauty, as other worlds above, and if we did our duty, it might be as full of love.</d>
    <a>Gerald Massey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="717">
    <d>Those that embrace the entire universe with love, for the most part love nothing, but their narrow selves.</d>
    <a>Johann Gottfried Von Herder</a>
  </q>
  <q id="718">
    <d>Those who haven&apos;t loved somebody else, more than they love themselves haven&apos;t even begun to live</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="719">
    <d>Those whom true love has held, it will go on holding.</d>
    <a>Seneca (Seneca the Elder)</a>
  </q>
  <q id="720">
    <d>Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself. Roman 13:9</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="721">
    <d>&apos;Tis said of love that it sometimes goes, sometimes flies; runs with one, walks gravely with another; turns a third into ice, and sets a fourth in a flame: it wounds one, another it kills: like lightning it begins and ends in the same moment: it makes that fort yield at night which it besieged but in the morning; for there is no force able to resist it.</d>
    <a>Miguel de Cervantes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="722">
    <d>To always be loved one must ever be agreeable.</d>
    <a>Mary Wortley Montagu</a>
  </q>
  <q id="723">
    <d>To an ordinary human being, love means nothing if it does not mean loving some people more than others.</d>
    <a>George Orwell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="724">
    <d>To be able to say how much love, is love but little.</d>
    <a>Francesco Petrarch</a>
  </q>
  <q id="725">
    <d>To be among people one loves, that&apos;s sufficient; to dream, to speak to them, to be silent among them, to think of indifferent things; but among them, everything is equal.</d>
    <a>Jean De La Bruyere</a>
  </q>
  <q id="726">
    <d>To be brave is to love someone unconditionally, without expecting anything in return. To just give. That takes courage, because we don&apos;t want to fall on our faces or leave ourselves open to hurt. </d>
    <a>Madonna</a>
  </q>
  <q id="727">
    <d>To be in love is merely to be in a perpetual state of anesthesia.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="728">
    <d>To fail to love is not to exist at all.</d>
    <a>Mark Van Doren</a>
  </q>
  <q id="729">
    <d>To fall in love is easy, even to remain in it is not difficult; our human loneliness is cause enough.  But it is a hard quest worth making to find a comrade through whose steady presence one becomes steadily the person one desires to be.</d>
    <a>Anna Louise Strong</a>
  </q>
  <q id="730">
    <d>To fall in love is to create a religion that has a fallible god.</d>
    <a>Jorge Luis Borges</a>
  </q>
  <q id="731">
    <d>To fear love is to fear life, and those who fear life are already three parts dead.</d>
    <a>Bertrand Russell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="732">
    <d>To live is like love, all reason is against it, and all healthy instinct for it.</d>
    <a>Samuel Butler</a>
  </q>
  <q id="733">
    <d>To love a thing means wanting it to live.</d>
    <a>Confucius</a>
  </q>
  <q id="734">
    <d>To love abundantly is to live abundantly, and to love forever is to live forever.</d>
    <a>Henry Drummond</a>
  </q>
  <q id="735">
    <d>To love and be loved is the great happiness of existence.</d>
    <a>Sydney Smith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="736">
    <d>To love and win is the best thing. To love and lose, the next best.</d>
    <a>William Makepeace Thackeray</a>
  </q>
  <q id="737">
    <d>To love another person is to see the face of God. Les Miserables</d>
    <a>Victor Hugo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="738">
    <d>To love deeply in one direction makes us more loving in all others. </d>
    <a>Anne-Sophie Swetchine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="739">
    <d>To love is to place our happiness in the happiness of another.</d>
    <a>Gottfried Wilhelm Von Leibniz</a>
  </q>
  <q id="740">
    <d>To love is to receive a glimpse of heaven.</d>
    <a>Karen Sunde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="741">
    <d>To love one child and to love all children, whether living or dead -somewhere these two loves come together. To love a no-good but humble punk and to love an honest man who believes himself to be an honest man -somewhere these, too, come together.</d>
    <a>Marguerite Duras</a>
  </q>
  <q id="742">
    <d>To love one person with a private love is poor and miserable: to love all is glorious.</d>
    <a>Thomas Traherne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="743">
    <d>To love without role, without power plays, is revolution.</d>
    <a>Rita Mae Brown</a>
  </q>
  <q id="744">
    <d>To love, for us men, is to clasp one woman with our arms, feeling that she lives and breathes just as we do, suffers as we do, thinks with us, loves with us, and, above all, sins with us.</d>
    <a>Baroness Emmuska Orczy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="745">
    <d>To say the truth, reason and love keep little company together now-a-days.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="746">
    <d>To try to write love is to confront the muck of language: that region of hysteria where language is both too much and too little, excessive and impoverished.</d>
    <a>Roland Barthes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="747">
    <d>Today I begin to understand what love must be, if it exists. When we are parted, we each feel the lack of the other half of ourselves. We are incomplete like a book in two volumes of which the first has been lost. That is what I imagine love to be: incompleteness in absence.</d>
    <a>Edmond de Goncourt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="748">
    <d>Together, we&apos;ll live with the sadness. I&apos;ll love you with all the madness in my soul.</d>
    <a>Koushun Takami</a>
  </q>
  <q id="749">
    <d>Treasure the love you receive above all. It will survive long after your good health has vanished.</d>
    <a>Og Mandino</a>
  </q>
  <q id="750">
    <d>True love begins when nothing is looked for in return.</d>
    <a>Antoine de Saint-Exup?ry</a>
  </q>
  <q id="751">
    <d>True love brings up everything - you&apos;re allowing a mirror to be held up to you daily. </d>
    <a>Jennifer Aniston</a>
  </q>
  <q id="752">
    <d>True love comes quietly, without banners or flashing lights. If you hear bells, get your ears checked.</d>
    <a>Erich Segal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="753">
    <d>True love comes quietly, without banners or flashing lights. If you hear bells, get your ears checked.</d>
    <a>Erich Segal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="754">
    <d>True love grows by sacrifice and the more thoroughly the soul rejects natural satisfaction the stronger and more detached its tenderness becomes.</d>
    <a>St. Theresa of Lisieux</a>
  </q>
  <q id="755">
    <d>True love is like ghosts, which everyone talks about and few have seen.</d>
    <a>Fran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="756">
    <d>True love is like ghosts, which everyone talks about and few have seen.</d>
    <a>La Rochefoucauld</a>
  </q>
  <q id="757">
    <d>True love is night jasmine, a diamond in darkness, the heartbeat no cardiologist has ever heard. It is the most common of miracles, fashioned of fleecy clouds - a handful of stars tossed into the night sky.</d>
    <a>Jim Bishop</a>
  </q>
  <q id="758">
    <d>True love is the parent of humility.</d>
    <a>William Ellery Channing</a>
  </q>
  <q id="759">
    <d>True love makes the thought of death frequent, easy, without terrors; it merely becomes the standard of comparison, the price one would pay for many things.</d>
    <a>Henri B. Stendhal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="760">
    <d>True love means two seeds grow separately until they join in Matrimony forever.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="761">
    <d>True love stories never have endings.</d>
    <a>Richard Bach</a>
  </q>
  <q id="762">
    <d>Truly loving another means letting go of all expectations. It means full acceptance, even celebration of another&apos;s personhood.</d>
    <a>Karen Casey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="763">
    <d>Two halves have little choice but to join;And yes, they do make a wholebut two wholes when they coincide...That is beauty.That is love.</d>
    <a>Peter McWilliams</a>
  </q>
  <q id="764">
    <d>Two persons love in one another the future good which they aid one another to unfold.</d>
    <a>Margaret Fuller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="765">
    <d>Two separate, distinct personalities, not separate at all, but inextricably bound, soul and body and mind, to each other, how did we get so far apart so fast?</d>
    <a>Judith Guest</a>
  </q>
  <q id="766">
    <d>We all suffer from the preoccupation that there exists ... in the loved one, perfection.</d>
    <a>Sidney Poitier</a>
  </q>
  <q id="767">
    <d>We always come back to our first love.</d>
    <a>Etienne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="768">
    <d>We always deceive ourselves twice about the people we love - first to their advantage, then to their disadvantage.</d>
    <a>Albert Camus</a>
  </q>
  <q id="769">
    <d>We are all born for love. It is the principle of existence, and its only end.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Disraeli</a>
  </q>
  <q id="770">
    <d>We are nearer loving those who hate us than those who love us more than we wish.</d>
    <a>Fran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="771">
    <d>We are never so defenseless against suffering as when we love, never so forlornly unhappy as when we have lost our love object or its love.</d>
    <a>Sigmund Freud</a>
  </q>
  <q id="772">
    <d>We are not commanded (or forbidden) to love our mates, our children, our friends, our country because such affections come naturally to us and are good in themselves, although we may corrupt them. We are commanded to love our neighbor because our natural attitude toward the other is one of either indifference or hostility.</d>
    <a>W. H. Auden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="773">
    <d>We are not the same persons this year as last; nor are those we love. It is a happy chance if we, changing, continue to love a changed person.</d>
    <a>W. Somerset Maugham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="774">
    <d>We are shaped and fashioned by what we love.</d>
    <a>Johann Wolfgang von Goethe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="775">
    <d>We are shaped and fashioned by what whom we love.</d>
    <a>Johann von Goethe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="776">
    <d>We can only learn to love by loving.</d>
    <a>Iris Murdoch</a>
  </q>
  <q id="777">
    <d>We can recognize the dawn and the decline of love by the uneasiness we feel when alone together.</d>
    <a>Jean De La Bruyere</a>
  </q>
  <q id="778">
    <d>We cannot really love anybody with whom we never laugh.</d>
    <a>Agnes Repplier</a>
  </q>
  <q id="779">
    <d>We cease loving ourselves if no one loves us.</d>
    <a>Germaine De Stael</a>
  </q>
  <q id="780">
    <d>We conceal it from ourselves in vain - we must always love something. In those matters seemingly removed from love, the feeling is secretly to be found, and man cannot possibly live for a moment without it.</d>
    <a>Blaise Pascal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="781">
    <d>We don&apos;t believe in rheumatism and true love until after the first attack.</d>
    <a>Marie E. Eschenbach</a>
  </q>
  <q id="782">
    <d>We know that we have passed from death into life, because we love... 1 John 3:14</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="783">
    <d>We live in the world when we love it.</d>
    <a>Rabindranath Tagore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="784">
    <d>We love because it&apos;s the only true adventure.</d>
    <a>Nikki Giovanni</a>
  </q>
  <q id="785">
    <d>We love but once, for once only are we perfectly equipped for loving.</d>
    <a>Cyril Connolly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="786">
    <d>We love in another&apos;s soul whatever of ourselves we can deposit in it; the greater the deposit, the greater the love.</d>
    <a>Irving Layton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="787">
    <d>We love those who admire us, but not those whom we admire.</d>
    <a>Fran</a>
  </q>
  <q id="788">
    <d>We must accept finite disappointment, but never lose infinite hope.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther King</a>
  </q>
  <q id="789">
    <d>We must love one another or die.</d>
    <a>W. H. Auden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="790">
    <d>We perceive when love begins and when it declines by our embarrassment when alone together.</d>
    <a> La Bruy?re</a>
  </q>
  <q id="791">
    <d>We really have to understand the person we want to love. If our love is only a will to possess, it is not love. If we only think of ourselves, if we know only our own needs and ignore the needs of the other person, we cannot love.</d>
    <a>Thich Nhat Hanh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="792">
    <d>We that are true lovers run into strange capers.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="793">
    <d>We were two and had but one heart between us.</d>
    <a>Francois de Montcorbier Villon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="794">
    <d>We who were loved will never unlive that crippling fever.</d>
    <a>Adrienne Rich</a>
  </q>
  <q id="795">
    <d>We will invent new lullabies, new songs, new acts of love, we will cry over things we used to laugh and our new wisdom will bring tears to eyes of gentle creatures from other planets who were afraid of us till then and in the end a summer with wild winds and new friends will be.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="796">
    <d>We&apos;ve got this gift of love, but love is like a precious plant. You can&apos;t just accept it and leave it in the cupboard or just think it&apos;s going to get on by itself. You&apos;ve got to keep watering it. You&apos;ve got to really look after it and nurture it.</d>
    <a>John Lennon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="797">
    <d>What does love look like? It has the hands to help others. It has the feet to hasten to the poor and needy. It has eyes to see misery and want. It has the ears to hear the sighs and sorrows of men. That is what love looks like.</d>
    <a>Saint Augustine of Hippo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="798">
    <d>What else is love but understanding and rejoicing in the fact that another person lives, acts, and experiences otherwise than we do? </d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="799">
    <d>What force is more potent than love?</d>
    <a>Igor Stravinsky</a>
  </q>
  <q id="800">
    <d>What is love? It is the morning and the evening star.</d>
    <a>Sinclair Lewis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="801">
    <d>What is the main thing in love? to know and to hide. To know about the one you love and to hide that you love. At times the hiding (shame) overpowers the knowing (passion). The passion for the hidden - the passion for the revealed.</d>
    <a>Marina Ivanova Tsvetaeva</a>
  </q>
  <q id="802">
    <d>What most people need to learn in life is how to love people and use things instead of using people and loving things.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="803">
    <d>What the world really needs is more love and less paper work.</d>
    <a>Pearl Bailey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="804">
    <d>What then in love can woman do? If we grow fond they shun us. And when we fly them, they pursue: But leave us when they&apos;ve won us.</d>
    <a>John Gay</a>
  </q>
  <q id="805">
    <d>What was the point of having unending life if that life was without love?</d>
    <a>Claudia Gray</a>
  </q>
  <q id="806">
    <d>What will not woman, gentle woman dare; when strong affection stirs her spirit up?</d>
    <a>Robert Southey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="807">
    <d>Whatever our souls are made of, his and mine are the same.</d>
    <a>Emily Bronte</a>
  </q>
  <q id="808">
    <d>What&apos;s so remarkable about Love at first sight? It&apos;s when people have been looking at each other for years that it becomes remarkable.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="809">
    <d>What&apos;s terrible is to pretend that the second-rate is first-rate, that you don&apos;t need love when you do or that you like your work when you know quite well you&apos;re capable of better.</d>
    <a>Doris Lessing</a>
  </q>
  <q id="810">
    <d>When a man and a woman have an overwhelming passion for each other, it seems to me, in spite of such obstacles dividing them as parents or husband, that they belong to each other in the name of Nature, and are lovers by Divine right, in spite of human convention or the laws.</d>
    <a>Nicolas Chamfort</a>
  </q>
  <q id="811">
    <d>When a man and a woman have an overwhelming passion for each other, it seems to me, in spite of such obstacles dividing them as parents or husband, that they belong to each other in the name of Nature, and are lovers by Divine right, in spite of human convention or the laws.</d>
    <a>Sebastian Roch Nicolas Chamfort</a>
  </q>
  <q id="812">
    <d>When a man has once loved a woman, he will do anything for her, except continue to love her.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="813">
    <d>When Death to either shall come - I pray it be first to me.</d>
    <a>Robert Bridges</a>
  </q>
  <q id="814">
    <d>When desire, having rejected reason and overpowered judgment which leads to right, is set in the direction of the pleasure which beauty can inspire, and when again under the influence of its kindred desires it is moved with violent motion towards the beauty of corporeal forms, it acquires a surname from this very violent motion, and is called love.</d>
    <a>Socrates</a>
  </q>
  <q id="815">
    <d>When first we met we did not guess that Love would prove so hard a master.</d>
    <a>Robert Bridges</a>
  </q>
  <q id="816">
    <d>When I have learnt to love God better than my earthly dearest, I shall love my earthly dearest better than I do now. In so far as I learn to love my earthly dearest at the expense of God and instead of God, I shall be moving towards the state in which I shall not love my earthly dearest at all. When first things are put first, second things are not suppressed but increased.</d>
    <a>C.S. Lewis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="817">
    <d>When I look on you a moment, then I can speak no more, but my tongue falls silent, and at once a delicate flame courses beneath my skin, and with my eyes I see nothing, and my ears hum, and a wet sweat bathes me and a trembling seizes me all over.</d>
    <a> Sappho</a>
  </q>
  <q id="818">
    <d>When love begins to sicken and decay it uses an enforced ceremony. Julius Caesar</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="819">
    <d>When two people relate to each other authentically and humanly, God is the electricity that surges between them.</d>
    <a>Martin Buber</a>
  </q>
  <q id="820">
    <d>When we are in love we seem to ourselves quite different from what we were before.</d>
    <a>Blaise Pascal</a>
  </q>
  <q id="821">
    <d>When we lose one we love, our bitterest tears are called forth by the memory of hours when we love not enough.</d>
    <a>Maurice Maeterlinck</a>
  </q>
  <q id="822">
    <d>When we understand that man is the only animal who must create meaning, who must open a wedge into neutral nature, we already understand the essence of love. Love is the problem of an animal who must find life, create a dialogue with nature in order to experience his own being.</d>
    <a>Ernest Becker</a>
  </q>
  <q id="823">
    <d>When you give each other everything, it becomes an even trade. Each wins all. </d>
    <a>Lois McMaster Bujold</a>
  </q>
  <q id="824">
    <d>When you interact with another, an illusion is part of this dynamic. This illusion allows each soul to perceive what it needs to understands in order to heal.</d>
    <a>Gary Zukav</a>
  </q>
  <q id="825">
    <d>When you love someone all your saved-up wishes start coming out.</d>
    <a>Elizabeth Bowen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="826">
    <d>When you love someone, all your saved-up wishes start coming out.</d>
    <a>Elisabeth Bowen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="827">
    <d>Whenever you are confronted with an opponent. Conquer him with love.</d>
    <a>Mahatma Gandhi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="828">
    <d>Where both deliberate, the love is slight: Who ever lov&apos;d, that lov&apos;d not at first sight?</d>
    <a>Christopher Marlowe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="829">
    <d>Where love and wisdom drink out of the same cup, in this everyday world, it is the exception.</d>
    <a>Madame Neckar</a>
  </q>
  <q id="830">
    <d>Where love is concerned, too much is not even enough.</d>
    <a>Pierre De Beaumarchais</a>
  </q>
  <q id="831">
    <d>Where love rules, there is no will to power; where power predominates, there love is lacking. The one is the shadow of the other.</d>
    <a>Carl Gustav Jung</a>
  </q>
  <q id="832">
    <d>Where there is love there is life.</d>
    <a>Mahatma Gandhi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="833">
    <d>Where we love is home, home that our feet may leave, but not our hearts.</d>
    <a>Oliver Wendell Holmes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="834">
    <d>Wherever your heart is, that is where you&apos;ll find your treasure.</d>
    <a>Paulo Coelho</a>
  </q>
  <q id="835">
    <d>Whether life is worth living depends on whether there is love in life.</d>
    <a>R. D. Laing</a>
  </q>
  <q id="836">
    <d>Who can give law to lovers? Love is a greater law to itself.</d>
    <a>Boethius (Anicius Manlius Severinus)</a>
  </q>
  <q id="837">
    <d>Who dares deny that this is true: The whole is more than all its parts?A whole love than divided love,Or than half love from fifty hearts?Yet who dare either this deny:The part is more than is the whole?That treasures halved with one dear loveAre more than double to the soul?</d>
    <a>Arthur Dillon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="838">
    <d>Who ever loved that loved not at first sight?</d>
    <a>Christopher Marlowe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="839">
    <d>Who is wise in love, love most, say least.</d>
    <a>Alfred Lord Tennyson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="840">
    <d>Who loves, raves.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="841">
    <d>Who so loves believes the impossible.</d>
    <a>Elizabeth Barrett Browning</a>
  </q>
  <q id="842">
    <d>Who travels for love finds a thousand miles not longer than one.</d>
    <a>Japanese Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="843">
    <d>Wicked men obey from fear; good men, from love.</d>
    <a>Aristotle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="844">
    <d>Without His love I can do nothing, with His love there is nothing I cannot do.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="845">
    <d>Woe is me! The winged words on which my soul would pierceInto the heights of love&apos;s rare universe,Are chains of lead around its flight of fire-I pant, I sink, I tremble, I expire.</d>
    <a>Percy Bysshe Shelley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="846">
    <d>Woe to the man whose heart has not learned while young to hope, to love - and to put its trust in life.</d>
    <a>Joseph Conrad</a>
  </q>
  <q id="847">
    <d>Women are often under the impression that men are much more madly in love with them than they really are. </d>
    <a>W. Somerset Maugham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="848">
    <d>Women wish to be loved not because they are pretty, or good, or well bred, or graceful, or intelligent, but because they are themselves.</d>
    <a>Henri Frederic Amiel</a>
  </q>
  <q id="849">
    <d>Yes, I do touch. I believe that everyone needs that</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="850">
    <d>Yet each man kills the thing he loves from all let this be heard some does it with a bitter look some with a flattering word the coward does it with a kiss the brave man with the sword.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="851">
    <d>You are my life. You&apos;re the only thing it would hurt to lose.</d>
    <a>Stephenie Meyer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="852">
    <d>You are my lover and I am your mistress and kingdoms and empires and governments have tottered and succumbed before now to that mighty combination.</d>
    <a>Violet Trefusis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="853">
    <d>You call it madness, but I call it love.</d>
    <a>Don Byas</a>
  </q>
  <q id="854">
    <d>You can give without loving, but you cannot love without giving.</d>
    <a>Ami Carmichael</a>
  </q>
  <q id="855">
    <d>You can give without loving, but you cannot love without giving.</d>
    <a>Amy Carmichael</a>
  </q>
  <q id="856">
    <d>You can&apos;t buy love, but you can pay heavily for it.</d>
    <a>Henny Youngman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="857">
    <d>You can&apos;t love anyone until you understand that you can&apos;t love everyone. </d>
    <a>Real Live Preacher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="858">
    <d>You can&apos;t put a price tag on love, but you can on all its accessories.</d>
    <a>Melanie Clark</a>
  </q>
  <q id="859">
    <d>You can&apos;t show love to someone at the expense of someone else who loves you. </d>
    <a>Randy K. Milholland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="860">
    <d>You come to love not by finding the perfect person, but by seeing an imperfect person perfectly.</d>
    <a>Sam Keen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="861">
    <d>You couldn&apos;t get a clue during the clue mating season in a field full of horny clues if you smeared your body with clue musk and did the clue mating dance.</d>
    <a>Edward Flaherty</a>
  </q>
  <q id="862">
    <d>You don&apos;t love a woman because she is beautiful, but she is beautiful because you love her.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="863">
    <d>You have to walk carefully in the beginning of love; the running across fields into your lover&apos;s arms can only come later when you&apos;re sure they won&apos;t laugh if you trip.</d>
    <a>Jonathan Carroll</a>
  </q>
  <q id="864">
    <d>You will find as you look back upon your life that the moments when you have truly lived are the moments when you have done things in the spirit of love.</d>
    <a>Henry Drummond</a>
  </q>
  <q id="865">
    <d>Young love is a flame; very pretty, often very hot and fierce, but still only light and flickering. The love of the older and disciplined heart is as coals, deep-burning, unquenchable.</d>
    <a>Henry Ward Beecher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="866">
    <d>You&apos;re in love. That makes you actually kind of boring to people who aren&apos;t in love.</d>
    <a>Claudia Gray</a>
  </q>
  <q id="867">
    <d>I will remember always that marriage, like life, is a journey - not a destination - and that its treasures are found not just at the end but all along the way.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="868">
    <d>Weeping bride, laughing wife, laughing bride, weeping wife.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="869">
    <d>Marry a mountain girl and you marry the whole mountain.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="870">
    <d>Do not choose your wife at a dance, but in the field among the harvesters.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="871">
    <d>Choose your wife as you wish your children to be.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="872">
    <d>Those that marry for money sell their liberty.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="873">
    <d>Three things drive a man outdoors; smoke, a leaking roof and a scolding wife.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="874">
    <d>You&apos;ll repent if you marry, and repent if you don&apos;t.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="875">
    <d>Marrying is easy, it&apos;s housework that&apos;s hard.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="876">
    <d>A good wife and health is a mans best wealth.</d>
    <a>Proverb</a>
  </q>
  <q id="877">
    <d>When a match has equal partners then I fear not.</d>
    <a>Aeschylus</a>
  </q>
  <q id="878">
    <d>Marriage is more than four bare legs in a bed.</d>
    <a>Hoshang N. Akhtar</a>
  </q>
  <q id="879">
    <d>When two people marry they become in the eyes of the law one person, and that one person is the husband!</d>
    <a>Shana Alexander</a>
  </q>
  <q id="880">
    <d>If a man works like a horse for his money, there are a lot of girls anxious to take him down the bridal path.</d>
    <a>Marty Allen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="881">
    <d>The lion and the calf will lay down together, but the calf won&apos;t get much sleep..</d>
    <a>Woody Allen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="882">
    <d>To marry unequally is to suffer equally.</d>
    <a>Henri Frederic Amiel</a>
  </q>
  <q id="883">
    <d>Marriage is that relation between man and woman in which the independence is equal, the dependence mutual, and the obligation reciprocal.</d>
    <a>Louis K. Anspacher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="884">
    <d>To marry a man out of pity is folly; and, if you think you are going to influence the kind of fellow who has never had a chance, poor devil, you are profoundly mistaken. One can only influence the strong characters in life, not the weak; and it is the height of vanity to suppose that you can make an honest man of anyone.</d>
    <a>Margot Asquith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="885">
    <d>Like everything which is not the involuntary result of fleeting emotion but the creation of time and will, any marriage, happy or unhappy, is infinitely more interesting than any romance, however passionate.</d>
    <a>W. H. Auden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="886">
    <d>An engaged woman is always more agreeable than a disengaged. She is satisfied with herself. Her cares are over, and she feels that she may exert all her powers of pleasing without suspicion. All is safe with a lady engaged; no harm can be done.</d>
    <a>Jane Austen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="887">
    <d>Wives are young men&apos;s mistresses; companions for middle age, and old men&apos;s nurses.</d>
    <a>Francis Bacon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="888">
    <d>A woman must be a genius to create a good husband.</d>
    <a>Honore de Balzac</a>
  </q>
  <q id="889">
    <d>It is easier to be a lover than a husband for the simple reason that it is more difficult to be witty every day than to say pretty things from time to time.</d>
    <a>Honore de Balzac</a>
  </q>
  <q id="890">
    <d>No man worth his salt, no man of spirit and spine, no man for whom I could have any respect, could rejoice in the identification of Tallulah&apos;s husband. It&apos;s tough enough to be bogged down in a legend. It would be even tougher to marry one.</d>
    <a>Tallulah Bankhead</a>
  </q>
  <q id="891">
    <d>I am thinking of taking a fifth wife. Why not? Solomon had a thousand wives and he is a synonym for wisdom.</d>
    <a>John Barrymore</a>
  </q>
  <q id="892">
    <d>Marriage is our last, best chance to grow up.</d>
    <a>Joseph Barth</a>
  </q>
  <q id="893">
    <d>The curse which lies upon marriage is that too often the individuals are joined in their weakness rather than in their strength - each asking from the other instead of finding pleasure in giving.</d>
    <a>Simone de Beauvoir</a>
  </q>
  <q id="894">
    <d>To catch a husband is an art; to hold him is a job.</d>
    <a>Simone de Beauvoir</a>
  </q>
  <q id="895">
    <d>Well married a person has wings, poorly married shackles.</d>
    <a>Henry Ward Beecher</a>
  </q>
  <q id="896">
    <d>Never marry a man who hates his mother, because he&apos;ll end up hating you.</d>
    <a>Jill Bennett</a>
  </q>
  <q id="897">
    <d>A good wife always forgives her husband when she&apos;s wrong.</d>
    <a>Milton Berle</a>
  </q>
  <q id="898">
    <d>Husbands, love your wives, just as Christ also loved the church and gave himself up for her. Ephesians 5:25</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="899">
    <d>Therefore shall a man leave his father and mother, and shall cleave unto his wife: and they shall be one flesh. Genesis 2:24</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="900">
    <d>For in the resurrection they neither marry, nor are given in marriage, but are as the angels of God in heaven. Matthew 22:30</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="901">
    <d>Who finds a wife finds a good thing, and obtains favor with the Lord.</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="902">
    <d>Husbands, in the same way be considerate as you live with your wives, and treat them with respect as the weaker partner and as heirs with you of the gracious gift of life, so that nothing will hinder your prayers. 1 Peter 3:7</d>
    <a>Bible</a>
  </q>
  <q id="903">
    <d>Incompatibility. In matrimony a similarity of tastes, particularly the taste for domination.</d>
    <a>Ambrose Bierce</a>
  </q>
  <q id="904">
    <d>The world has suffered more from the ravages of ill-advised marriages than from virginity.</d>
    <a>Ambrose Bierce</a>
  </q>
  <q id="905">
    <d>Marriage. The state or condition of a community consisting of a master, a mistress and two slaves, making in all, two.</d>
    <a>Ambrose Bierce</a>
  </q>
  <q id="906">
    <d>I recently read that love is entirely a matter of chemistry. That must be why my wife treats me like toxic waste.</d>
    <a>David Bissonette</a>
  </q>
  <q id="907">
    <d>Meek wifehood is no part of my profession; I am your friend, but never your possession.</d>
    <a>Vera Brittain</a>
  </q>
  <q id="908">
    <d>Marriage is not just spiritual communion, it is also remembering to take out the trash.</d>
    <a>Joyce Brothers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="909">
    <d>Marriage, it seems, confines every man to his proper rank.</d>
    <a>Jean De La Bruyere</a>
  </q>
  <q id="910">
    <d>The bitterest creature under heaven is the wife who discovers that her husband&apos;s bravery is only bravado, that his strength is only a uniform, that his power is but a gun in the hands of a fool.</d>
    <a>Pearl Buck</a>
  </q>
  <q id="911">
    <d>Husbands are awkward things to deal with; even keeping them in hot water will not make them tender.</d>
    <a>Mary Buckley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="912">
    <d>Once a boy becomes a man, he&apos;s a man all his life, but a woman is only sexy until she becomes your wife.</d>
    <a>Al Bundy</a>
  </q>
  <q id="913">
    <d>The only thing that holds a marriage together is the husband being big enough to keep his mouth shut, to step back and see where his wife is wrong.</d>
    <a>Archie Bunker</a>
  </q>
  <q id="914">
    <d>The aura of the theocratic death penalty for adultery still clings to America, even outside New England, and multiple divorce, which looks to the European like serial polygamy, is the moral solution to the problem of the itch. Love comes into it too, of course, but in Europe we tend to see marital love as an eternity which encompasses hate and also indifference: when we promise to love we really mean that we promise to honor a contract. Americans, seeming to take marriage with not enough seriousness, are really taking love and sex with too much.</d>
    <a>Anthony Burgess</a>
  </q>
  <q id="915">
    <d>One was never married, and that&apos;s his hell; another is, and that&apos;s his plague.</d>
    <a>Robert Burton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="916">
    <d>I am about to be married, and am of course in all the misery of a man in pursuit of happiness.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="917">
    <d>Though women are angels, yet wedlock&apos;s the devil.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="918">
    <d>I have great hopes that we shall love each other all our lives as much as if we had never married at all.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="919">
    <d>The fact is that my wife if she had common sense would have more power over me than any other whatsoever, for my heart always alights upon the nearest perch.</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="920">
    <d>All tragedies are finished by a death,All comedies are ended by a marriage;The future states of both are left to faith,For authors fear description might disparageThe worlds to come of both. . . .</d>
    <a>Lord (George Gordon) Byron</a>
  </q>
  <q id="921">
    <d>Love and marriage, love and marriage go together like a horse and carriage. Dad was told by mother. You can&apos;t have one without the other.</d>
    <a>Sammy Cahn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="922">
    <d>The deep, deep peace of the double-bed after the hurly-burly of the chaise-lounge.</d>
    <a>Mrs Patrick Campbell</a>
  </q>
  <q id="923">
    <d>If variety is the spice of life, marriage is the big can of leftover Spam.</d>
    <a>Johnny Carson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="924">
    <d>A man will teach his wife what is needed to arouse his desires. And there is no reason for a woman to know any more than what her husband is prepared to teach her. If she gets married knowing far too much about what she wants and doesn&apos;t want then she will be ready to find fault with her husband.</d>
    <a>Barbara Cartland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="925">
    <d>Marriage is an adventure, like going to war.</d>
    <a>G. K. Chesterton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="926">
    <d>Variability is one of the virtues of a woman. It avoids the crude requirement of polygamy. So long as you have one good wife you are sure to have a spiritual harem.</d>
    <a>G. K. Chesterton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="927">
    <d>An archaeologist is the best husband any woman can have: the older she gets, the more interested he is in her.</d>
    <a>Agatha Christie</a>
  </q>
  <q id="928">
    <d>If I was your wife Sir, I&apos;d poison you! Madam, if you were my wife, I&apos;d let you!</d>
    <a>Sir Winston Churchill</a>
  </q>
  <q id="929">
    <d>Nothing is more noble, nothing more venerable than fidelity. Faithfulness and truth are the most sacred excellences and endowments of the human mind.</d>
    <a>Marcus Tullius Cicero</a>
  </q>
  <q id="930">
    <d>Before marriage a man yearns for a woman. Afterward the y is silent.</d>
    <a>W. A. Clarke</a>
  </q>
  <q id="931">
    <d>The most happy marriage I can imagine to myselfwould be the union of a deaf man to a blind woman.</d>
    <a>Samuel Taylor Coleridge</a>
  </q>
  <q id="932">
    <d>I&apos;ve never yet met a man who could look after me. I don&apos;t need a husband. What I need is a wife.</d>
    <a>Joan Collins</a>
  </q>
  <q id="933">
    <d>Never join with your friend when he abuses his horse or his wife, unless the one is to be sold and the other to be buried.</d>
    <a>Charles Caleb Colton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="934">
    <d>Except for poverty, incompatibility, opposition of parents, absence of love on one side and of desire to marry on both, nothing stands in the way of our happy union.</d>
    <a>Cyril Connolly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="935">
    <d>The dread of loneliness is greater than the fear of bondage, so we get married.</d>
    <a>Cyril Connolly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="936">
    <d>The true index of a man&apos;s character is the health of his wife.</d>
    <a>Cyril Connolly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="937">
    <d>I never married because there was no need. I have three pets at home which answer the same purpose as a husband. I have a dog which growls every morning, a parrot which swears all afternoon and a cat that comes home late at night.</d>
    <a>Marie Corelli</a>
  </q>
  <q id="938">
    <d>Marriage is like a bank account. You put it in, you take it out, you lose interest.</d>
    <a>Irwin Cory</a>
  </q>
  <q id="939">
    <d>That married couples can live together day after day is a miracle the Vatican has overlooked.</d>
    <a>Bill Cosby</a>
  </q>
  <q id="940">
    <d>My wife and I lived all alone, contention was our only bone. I fought with her, she fought with me, and things went on right merrily. But now I live here by myself with hardly a damn thing on the shelf, and pass my days with little cheer since I have parted from my dear.</d>
    <a>Robert Creeley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="941">
    <d>The majority of persons choose their wives with as little prudence as they eat. They see a troll with nothing else to recommend her but a pair of thighs and choice hunkers, and so smart to void their seed that they marry her at once. They imagine they can live in marvelous contentment with handsome feet and ambrosial buttocks. Most men are accredited fools shortly after they leave the womb.</d>
    <a>Edward Dahlberg</a>
  </q>
  <q id="942">
    <d>Marriage is a matter of give and take, but so far I haven&apos;t been able to find anybody who&apos;ll take what I have to give.</d>
    <a>Cass Daley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="943">
    <d>Marriage is not a noun; it&apos;s a verb. It isn&apos;t something you get. It&apos;s something you do. It&apos;s the way you love your partner every day.</d>
    <a>Barbara De Angelis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="944">
    <d>The real act of marriage takes place in the heart, not in the ballroom or church or synagogue. It&apos;s a choice you make - not just on your wedding day, but over and over again - and that choice is reflected in the way you treat your husband or wife.</d>
    <a>Barbara De Angelis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="945">
    <d>The road to success is filled with women pushing their husbands along.</d>
    <a>Lord Thomas Dewar</a>
  </q>
  <q id="946">
    <d>I think like any marriage, especially when you&apos;ve had divorced parents like myself, you&apos;d want to try even harder to make it work.</d>
    <a>Princess of Wales Diana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="947">
    <d>Do let him read the papers. But not while you accusingly tiptoe around the room, or perch much like a silent bird of prey on the edge of your most uncomfortable chair. (He will read them anyway, and he should read them, so let him choose his own good time.) Don&apos;t make a big exit. Just go. But kiss him quickly, before you go, otherwise he might think you are angry; he is used to suspecting he is doing something wrong.</d>
    <a>Marlene Dietrich</a>
  </q>
  <q id="948">
    <d>A man would prefer to come home to an unmade bed and a happy woman than to a neatly made bed and an angry woman.</d>
    <a>Marlene Dietrich</a>
  </q>
  <q id="949">
    <d>Whatever you may look like, marry a man your own age - as your beauty fades, so will his eyesight.</d>
    <a>Phyllis Diller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="950">
    <d>When a man opens the car door for his wife, it&apos;s either a new car or a new wife.</d>
    <a>Prince Philip Edinburgh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="951">
    <d>Personally, I can&apos;t see why it would be any less romantic to find a husband in a nice four-color catalogue than in the average downtown bar at happy hour.</d>
    <a>Barbara Ehrenreich</a>
  </q>
  <q id="952">
    <d>Marriage is socialism among two people.</d>
    <a>Barbara Ehrenreich</a>
  </q>
  <q id="953">
    <d>Wasn&apos;t marriage, like life, unstimulating and unprofitable and somewhat empty when too well ordered and protected and guarded? Wasn&apos;t it finer, more splendid, more nourishing, when it was, like life itself, a mixture of the sordid and the magnificent; of mud and stars; of earth and flowers; of love and hate and laughter and tears and ugliness and beauty and hurt?</d>
    <a>Edna Ferber</a>
  </q>
  <q id="954">
    <d>Married life requires shared mystery even when all the facts are known.</d>
    <a>Richard Ford</a>
  </q>
  <q id="955">
    <d>Keep your eyes wide open before marriage, and half-shut afterwards.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Franklin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="956">
    <d>One good husband is worth two good wives, for the scarcer things are, the more they are valued.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Franklin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="957">
    <d>Where there is marriage without love, there will be love without marriage.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Franklin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="958">
    <d>An undutiful daughter will prove an unmanageable wife.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Franklin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="959">
    <d>Never take a wife till thou hast a house (and a fire) to put her in.</d>
    <a>Benjamin Franklin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="960">
    <d>Though bachelors be the strongest stakes, married men are the best binders, in the hedge of the commonwealth.</d>
    <a>Thomas Fuller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="961">
    <d>If you would have a good wife, marry one who has been a good daughter.</d>
    <a>Thomas Fuller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="962">
    <d>Deceive not thyself by over-expecting happiness in the married estate. Remember the nightingales which sing only some months in the spring, but commonly are silent when they have hatched their eggs, as if their mirth were turned into care for their young ones.</d>
    <a>Thomas Fuller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="963">
    <d>He knows little, who will tell his wife all he knows.</d>
    <a>Thomas Fuller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="964">
    <d>Choose a wife by your ear than your eye.</d>
    <a>Thomas Fuller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="965">
    <d>Husbands are like fires. They go out when unattended.</d>
    <a>Zsa Zsa Gabor</a>
  </q>
  <q id="966">
    <d>A man in love is incomplete until he has married - then he&apos;s finished.</d>
    <a>Zsa Zsa Gabor</a>
  </q>
  <q id="967">
    <d>I never hate a man enough to give him his diamonds back.</d>
    <a>Zsa Zsa Gabor</a>
  </q>
  <q id="968">
    <d>I first learned the concepts of non-violence in my marriage.</d>
    <a>Mahatma Gandhi</a>
  </q>
  <q id="969">
    <d>I hate to be a failure. I hate and regret the failure of my marriages. I would gladly give all my millions for just one lasting marital success.</d>
    <a>J. Paul Getty</a>
  </q>
  <q id="970">
    <d>When a wife has a good husband it is easily seen in her face.</d>
    <a>Johann von Goethe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="971">
    <d>In taking out an insurance policy one pays for it in dollars and cents, always at liberty to discontinue payments. If, however, woman&apos;s premium is a husband, she pays for it with her name, her privacy, her self-respect, her very life, until death doth part.</d>
    <a>Emma Goldman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="972">
    <d>Love, the strongest and deepest element in all life, the harbinger of hope, of joy, of ecstasy; love, the defier of all laws, of all conventions; love, the freest, the most powerful molder of human destiny; how can such an all-compelling force be synonymous with that poor little State and Church-begotten weed, marriage?</d>
    <a>Emma Goldman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="973">
    <d>I... chose my wife as she did her wedding-gown, not for a fine glossy surface, but such qualities as would wear well.</d>
    <a>Oliver Goldsmith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="974">
    <d>Every time a woman makes herself laugh at her husband&apos;s often-told jokes she betrays him. The man who looks at his woman and says What would I do without you? is already destroyed.</d>
    <a>Germaine Greer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="975">
    <d>I grew up in a very large family in a very small house. I never slept alone until after I was married.</d>
    <a>Lewis Grizzard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="976">
    <d>An ideal wife is one who remains faithful to you but tries to be just as charming as if she weren&apos;t.</d>
    <a>Sacha Guitry</a>
  </q>
  <q id="977">
    <d>Two souls and one thought, two hearts and one pulse.</d>
    <a>Halen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="978">
    <d>Such a wife as I want... must be young, handsome I lay most stress upon a good shape, sensible a little learning will do, well-bread, chaste, and tender. As to religion, a moderate stock will satisfy me. She must believe in God and hate a saint.</d>
    <a>Alexander Hamilton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="979">
    <d>Matrimony is the high sea for which no compass has yet to be invented.</d>
    <a>Heinrich Heine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="980">
    <d>If you want to sacrifice the admiration of many men for the criticism of one, go ahead, get married.</d>
    <a>Katharine Hepburn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="981">
    <d>She is a wife who is the soul of her husband.</d>
    <a>Hitopadesa</a>
  </q>
  <q id="982">
    <d>Marriage has for women many equivalents of joining a mass movement. It offers them a new purpose in life, a new future and a new identity (a new name). The boredom of spinsters and of women who can no longer find joy and fulfillment in marriage stems from an awareness of a barren, spoiled life. By embracing a holy cause and dedicating their energies and substance to its advancement, they find a new life full of purpose and meaning.</d>
    <a>Eric Hoffer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="983">
    <d>You know I won&apos;t turn over a new leaf I am so obstinate, but then I am no less obstinate in being your affectionate Husband.</d>
    <a>William Hogarth</a>
  </q>
  <q id="984">
    <d>Naggers always know what they are doing. They weigh up the risks, then they go on and on and on until they get what they want or until they get punched.</d>
    <a>Jools Holland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="985">
    <d>I should like to see any kind of a man, distinguishable from a gorilla that some good and even pretty woman could not shape a husband out of.</d>
    <a>Oliver Wendell Holmes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="986">
    <d>There is nothing nobler or more admirable than when two people who see eye to eye keep house as man and wife, confounding their enemies and delighting their friends.</d>
    <a>Homer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="987">
    <d>All marriages are happy it&apos;s living together afterwards that causes all the problems.</d>
    <a>Raymond Hull</a>
  </q>
  <q id="988">
    <d>Americans, who make more of marrying for love than any other people, also break up more or their marriages, but the figure reflects not so much the failure of love as the determination not to live without it.</d>
    <a>Morton Hunt</a>
  </q>
  <q id="989">
    <d>A marriage based on full confidence, based on complete and unqualified frankness on both sides; they are not keeping anything back; there&apos;s no deception underneath it all. If I might so put it, it&apos;s an agreement for the mutual forgiveness of sin.</d>
    <a>Henrik Ibsen</a>
  </q>
  <q id="990">
    <d>Marriage is the torment of one, the felicity of two, the strife and enmity of three.</d>
    <a>Washington Irving</a>
  </q>
  <q id="991">
    <d>Marriage is like wine. It is not properly judged until the second glass.</d>
    <a>Douglas William Jerrold</a>
  </q>
  <q id="992">
    <d>Marriage is a mistake every man should make.</d>
    <a>George Jessel</a>
  </q>
  <q id="993">
    <d>I think every woman&apos;s entitled to a middle husband she can forget.</d>
    <a>Adela Rogers St. Johns</a>
  </q>
  <q id="994">
    <d>By taking a second wife he pays the highest compliment to the first, by showing that she made him so happy as a married man, that he wishes to be so a second time.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="995">
    <d>It is not from reason and prudence that people marry, but from inclination.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="996">
    <d>Marriage is the best state for man in general, and every man is a worst man in proportion to the level he is unfit for marriage.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="997">
    <d>There is, indeed, nothing that so much seduces reason from vigilance, as the thought of passing life with an amiable woman.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="998">
    <d>Marriage has many pains, but celibacy has no pleasures.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="999">
    <d>A man is in general better pleased when he has a good dinner upon his table, than when his wife talks Greek.</d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1000">
    <d>Bigamy is having one husband too many. Monogamy is the same.</d>
    <a>Erica Jong</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1001">
    <d>There is a rhythm to the ending of a marriage just like the rhythm of a courtship -only backward. You try to start again but get into blaming over and over. Finally you are both worn out, exhausted, hopeless. Then lawyers are called in to pick clean the corpses. The death has occurred much earlier.</d>
    <a>Erica Jong</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1002">
    <d>Marrying a man is like buying something you&apos;ve been admiring for a long time in a shop window. You may love it when you get it home, but it doesn&apos;t always go with everything else in the house.</d>
    <a>Jean Kerr</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1003">
    <d>Not observation of a duty but liberty itself is the pledge that assures fidelity.</d>
    <a>Ellen Key</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1004">
    <d>Love is moral even without legal marriage, but marriage is immoral without love.</d>
    <a>Ellen Key</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1005">
    <d>Marriage brings one into fatal connection with custom and tradition, and traditions and customs are like the wind and weather, altogether incalculable.</d>
    <a>Soren Kierkegaard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1006">
    <d>Marriage is a lottery, but you can&apos;t tear up your ticket if you lose.</d>
    <a>F. M. Knowles</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1007">
    <d>Sensual pleasures have the fleeting brilliance of a comet; a happy marriage has the tranquillity of a lovely sunset.</d>
    <a>Ann Landers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1008">
    <d>All married couples should learn the art of battle as they should learn the art of making love. Good battle is objective and honest -never vicious or cruel. Good battle is healthy and constructive, and brings to a marriage the principle of equal partnership.</d>
    <a>Ann Landers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1009">
    <d>We must do our business faithfully, without trouble or disquiet, recalling our mind to God mildly, and with tranquility, as often as we find it wandering from him.</d>
    <a>Brother Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1010">
    <d>My whole working philosophy is that the only stable happiness for mankind is that it shall live married in blessed union to woman-kind -intimacy, physical and psychical between a man and his wife. I wish to add that my state of bliss is by no means perfect.</d>
    <a>D. H. (David Herbert) Lawrence</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1011">
    <d>Progress of a marriage: There was a time when you couldn&apos;t make me happy. Now the time has come when you can make me unhappy.</d>
    <a>Irving Layton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1012">
    <d>Many a man in love with a dimple makes the mistake of marrying the whole girl.</d>
    <a>Stephen Leacock</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1013">
    <d>I&apos;ve had the boyhood thing of being Elvis. Now I want to be with my best friend, and my best friend&apos;s my wife. Who could ask for anything more?</d>
    <a>John Lennon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1014">
    <d>Rituals are important. Nowadays it&apos;s hip not to be married. I&apos;m not interested in being hip.</d>
    <a>John Lennon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1015">
    <d>There is, hidden or flaunted, a sword between the sexes till an entire marriage reconciles them.</d>
    <a>C.S. Lewis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1016">
    <d>A man stays in touch with society by means of a wife.</d>
    <a>Michael Lipsey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1017">
    <d>There is no more lovely, friendly, and charming relationship, communion, or company than a good marriage.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1018">
    <d>Let the wife make the husband glad to come home, and let him make her sorry to see him leave.</d>
    <a>Martin Luther</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1019">
    <d>Marriages are made in heaven and consummated on Earth.</d>
    <a>John Lyly</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1020">
    <d>The best way to get husbands to do something is to suggest that perhaps they are too old to do it.</d>
    <a>Shirley Maclaine</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1021">
    <d>Come live with me, and be my love, and we will all the pleasures prove.</d>
    <a>Christopher Marlowe</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1022">
    <d>The problem with marriage is that it ends every night after making love, and it must be rebuilt every morning before breakfast.</d>
    <a>Gabriel Garcia Marquez</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1023">
    <d>I belong to Bridegrooms Anonymous. Whenever I feel like getting married, they send over a lady in a housecoat and hair curlers to burn my toast for me.</d>
    <a>Dick Martin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1024">
    <d>The sum and substance of female education in America, as in England, is training women to consider marriage as the sole object in life, and to pretend that they do not think so.</d>
    <a>Harriet Martineau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1025">
    <d>Any one must see at a glance that if men and women marry those whom they do not love, they must love those whom they do not marry.</d>
    <a>Harriet Martineau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1026">
    <d>One of the best hearing aids a man can have is an attentive wife.</d>
    <a>Groucho Marx</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1027">
    <d>I was married by a judge. I should have asked for a jury.</d>
    <a>Groucho Marx</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1028">
    <d>A successful marriage is an edifice that must be rebuilt every day.</d>
    <a>Andr</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1029">
    <d>A marriage without conflicts is almost as inconceivable as a nation without crises.</d>
    <a>Andr</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1030">
    <d>A happy marriage is a long conversation which always seems too short.</d>
    <a>Andr</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1031">
    <d>Constancy is the complement of all other human virtues.</d>
    <a>Giuseppe Mazzini</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1032">
    <d>You can never be happily married to another until you get a divorce from yourself. A successful marriage demands a certain death to self.</d>
    <a>Jerry Mccant</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1033">
    <d>There&apos;s a way of transferring funds that is even faster than electronic banking. It&apos;s called marriage.</d>
    <a>Donald H. Mcgannon</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1034">
    <d>When a man brings his wife flowers for no reason, there&apos;s a reason.</d>
    <a>Molly Mcgee</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1035">
    <d>A successful marriage requires falling in love many times, always with the same person.</d>
    <a>Mignon McLaughlin</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1036">
    <d>The institution of marriage in all societies is a pattern within which the strains put by civilization on males and females alike must be resolved, a pattern within which men must learn, in return for a variety of elaborate rewards, new forms in which sexual spontaneity is still possible, and women must learn to discipline their receptivity to a thousand other considerations.</d>
    <a>Margaret Mead</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1037">
    <d>Strike an average between what a woman thinks of her husband a month before she marries him and what she thinks of him a year afterward, and you will have the truth about him.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1038">
    <d>Husbands never become good; they merely become proficient.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1039">
    <d>For it is mutual trust, even more than mutual interest that holds human associations together. Our friends seldom profit us but they make us feel safe. Marriage is a scheme to accomplish exactly that same end.</d>
    <a>H. L. Mencken</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1040">
    <d>After seven years of marriage, I&apos;m sure of two things - first, never wallpaper together, and second, you&apos;ll need two bathrooms.. both for her. The rest is a mystery, but a mystery I love to be involved in.</d>
    <a>Dennis Miller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1041">
    <d>Often the difference between a successful marriage and a mediocre one consists of leaving about three or four things a day unsaid.</d>
    <a>Harlan Miller</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1042">
    <d>Those graceful acts, those thousand decencies, that daily flow from all her words and actions, mixed with love and sweet compliance, which declare unfeigned union of mind, or in us both one soul.</d>
    <a>John Milton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1043">
    <d>Love is often the fruit of marriage.</d>
    <a>Moli</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1044">
    <d>We cannot do without it, and yet we disgrace and vilify the same. It may be compared to a cage, the birds without despair to get in, and those within despair to get out.</d>
    <a>Michel de Montaigne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1045">
    <d>Marriage is like a cage; one sees the birds outside desperate to get in, and those inside desperate to get out.</d>
    <a>Michel de Montaigne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1046">
    <d>If there is such a thing as a good marriage, it is because it resembles friendship rather than love.</d>
    <a>Michel de Montaigne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1047">
    <d>A good marriage would be between a blind wife and a deaf husband.</d>
    <a>Michel de Montaigne</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1048">
    <d>Marriage should be a duet-when one sings, the other claps.</d>
    <a>Joe Murray</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1049">
    <d>Successful marriage is always a triangle: a man, a woman, and God.</d>
    <a>Cecil Myers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1050">
    <d>There is only one thing for a man to do who is married to a woman who enjoys spending money, and that is enjoy earning it.</d>
    <a>Ogden Nash</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1051">
    <d>To keep your marriage brimming, with love in the wedding cup, whenever you&apos;re wrong, admit it; whenever you&apos;re right, shut up.</d>
    <a>Ogden Nash</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1052">
    <d>If you are really Master of your Fate, it shouldn&apos;t make any difference to you whether Cleopatra or the Bearded Lady is your mate.</d>
    <a>Ogden Nash</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1053">
    <d>A little incompatibility is the spice of life, as long as he has income and she is pattable.</d>
    <a>Ogden Nash</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1054">
    <d>The secret to a happy marriage is to tell your spouse everything, but the essentials.</d>
    <a>Cynthia Nelms</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1055">
    <d>A good marriage is at least 80 percent good luck in finding the right person at the right time. The rest is trust.</d>
    <a>Nanette Newman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1056">
    <d>The best friend is likely to acquire the best wife, because a good marriage is based on the talent for friendship.</d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1057">
    <d>It is obvious that all sense has gone out of modern marriage: which is, however, no objection to marriage but to modernity.</d>
    <a>Friedrich Nietzsche</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1058">
    <d>Only as far as a man is happily married to himself is he fit for married life and family life in general.</d>
    <a>Novalis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1059">
    <d>Quarrels are the dowry which married folk bring one another.</d>
    <a>Ovid</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1060">
    <d>My wife isn&apos;t married to me forever; she&apos;s married to me for good. That keeps me on my toes.</d>
    <a>Mal Pancoast</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1061">
    <d>Oh, it is sure as it is sad That any lad is every lad, And what&apos;s a girl, to dare implore Her dear be hers forevermore? Though he be tried and he be bold, And swearing death should he be cold, He&apos;ll run the path the others went.... But you, my sweet, are different.</d>
    <a>Dorothy Parker</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1062">
    <d>Fidelity is seven-tenths of business success.</d>
    <a>James Parton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1063">
    <d>In marriage do thou be wise; prefer the person before money; virtue before beauty; the mind before the body.</d>
    <a>William Penn</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1064">
    <d>I never wanted to get married. The last thing I wanted was infinite security and to be the place an arrow shoots off from. I wanted change and excitement and to shoot off in all directions myself, like the colored arrows from a Fourth of July rocket.</d>
    <a>Sylvia Plath</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1065">
    <d>Marriage is an act of will that signifies and involves a mutual gift, which unites the spouses and binds them to their eventual souls, with whom they make up a sole family -a domestic church.</d>
    <a>Pope John Paul II</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1066">
    <d>It ought to be illegal for an artist to marry. If the artist must marry let him find someone more interested in art, or his art, or the artist part of him, than in him. After which let them take tea together three times a week.</d>
    <a>Ezra Pound</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1067">
    <d>Be to their virtue very kind; be to their faults a little blind.</d>
    <a>Matthew Prior</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1068">
    <d>Your marriage moves toward a state of isolation. Unless you lovingly and energetically nurture your marriage, you will begin to drift away from your mate.</d>
    <a>Dennis Rainey</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1069">
    <d>Marriage is a lottery in which men stake their liberty and women their happiness.</d>
    <a>Madame De Rieux</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1070">
    <d>The clog of all pleasure, the luggage of life, is the best can be said for a very good wife.</d>
    <a>Earl Rochester</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1071">
    <d>Plant and your spouse plants with you; weed and you weed alone.</d>
    <a>Jean Jacques Rousseau</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1072">
    <d>A husband is what&apos;s left of the lover after the nerve has been extracted.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1073">
    <d>A bride at her second marriage does not wear a veil. She wants to see what she is getting.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1074">
    <d>After marriage, a woman&apos;s sight becomes so keen that she can see right through her husband without looking at him, and a man&apos;s so dull that he can look right through his wife without seeing her.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1075">
    <d>Before marriage, a man will go home and lie awake all night thinking about something you said; after marriage, he&apos;ll go to sleep before you finish saying it.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1076">
    <d>Marriage is the miracle that transforms a kiss from a pleasure into a duty.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1077">
    <d>Marriage is the operation by which a woman&apos;s vanity and a man&apos;s egotism are extracted without an anaesthetic.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1078">
    <d>No girl who is going to marry need bother to win a college degree; she just naturally becomes a Master of Arts and a Doctor of Philosophy after catering to an ordinary man for a few years.</d>
    <a>Helen Rowland</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1079">
    <d>In the perfect wedlock, the man, I should say, is the head, but the woman the heart, with which he cannot dispense.</d>
    <a>Ruckett</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1080">
    <d>I think men who have a pierced ear are better prepared for marriage. They&apos;ve experienced pain and bought jewelry.</d>
    <a>Rita Rudner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1081">
    <d>Nature admits of no permanence in the relation between man and woman. It is only man&apos;s egoism that wants to keep woman like some buried treasure. All endeavors to introduce permanence in love, the most changeable thing in this changeable human existence, have gone shipwreck in spite of religious ceremonies, vows, and legalities.</d>
    <a>Leopold Von Sacher-Masoch</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1082">
    <d>By faithfulness we are collected and wound up into unity within ourselves, whereas we had been scattered abroad in multiplicity.</d>
    <a>Saint Augustine of Hippo</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1083">
    <d>It takes two to make a marriage a success and only one to make it a failure.</d>
    <a>Herbert Samuel</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1084">
    <d>The philosophy of the common man is an old wife that gives him no pleasure, yet he cannot live without her, and resents any aspersions that strangers may cast on her character.</d>
    <a>George Santayana</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1085">
    <d>In our monogamous part of the world, to marry means to halve one&apos;s rights and double one&apos;s duties.</d>
    <a>Arthur Schopenhauer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1086">
    <d>A little weeping, a little wheedling, a little self-degradation, a little careful use of our advantages, and then some man will say .Come, be my wife! With good looks and youth marriage is easy to attain. There are men enough; but a woman who has sold herself, even for a ring and a new name, need hold her skirt aside for no creature in the street. They both earn their bread in one way. Marriage for love is the most beautiful external symbol of the union of souls; marriage without it is the least clean traffic that defiles the world.</d>
    <a>Olive Schreiner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1087">
    <d>Of all actions of a man&apos;s life, his marriage does least concern other people, yet of all actions of our life &apos;Tis most meddled with by other people.</d>
    <a>John Selden</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1088">
    <d>No sooner met but they looked; no sooner looked but they loved; no sooner loved but they sighed; no sooner sighed but they asked one another the reason; no sooner knew the reason but they sought the remedy; and in these degrees have they made a pair of stairs to marriage, which they will climb incontinent, or else be incontinent before marriage.</d>
    <a>William Shakespeare</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1089">
    <d>There is no subject on which more dangerous nonsense is talked and thought than marriage.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1090">
    <d>Marriage is popular because it combines the maximum of temptation with the maximum of opportunity.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1091">
    <d>When two people are under the influence of the most violent, most insane, most delusive, and most transient of passions, they are required to swear that they will remain in that excited, abnormal, and exhausting condition continuously until death do them part.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1092">
    <d>This comes of James teaching me to think for myself, and never to hold back out of fear of what other people may think of me. It works beautifully as long as I think the same things as he does.</d>
    <a>George Bernard Shaw</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1093">
    <d>My true-love hath my heart, and I have his,By just exchange, one for the other given:I hold his dear, and mine he cannot miss,There never was a better bargain driven.</d>
    <a>Sir Philip Sidney</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1094">
    <d>Chains do not hold a marriage together. It is threads, hundreds of tiny threads which sew people together through the years. That is what makes a marriage last -more than passion or even sex!</d>
    <a>Simone Signoret</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1095">
    <d>All men make mistakes, but married men find out about them sooner.</d>
    <a>Red Skelton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1096">
    <d>If a man truly wants to communicate with his wife, he must enter her world of emotions.</d>
    <a>Gary Smalley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1097">
    <d>Married couples resemble a pair of scissors, often moving in opposite directions, yet punishing anyone who gets in between them.</d>
    <a>Sydney Smith</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1098">
    <d>By all means marry. If you get a good wife you will become happy, and if you get a bad one you will become a philosopher.</d>
    <a>Socrates</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1099">
    <d>Marriage: A ceremony in which rings are put on the finger of the lady and through the nose of the gentleman.</d>
    <a>Herbert Spencer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1100">
    <d>The marriage state, with and without the affection suitable to it, is the completest image of Heaven and Hell we are capable of receiving in this life.</d>
    <a>Sir Richard Steele</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1101">
    <d>A journey is like marriage. The certain way to be wrong is to think you control it.</d>
    <a>John Steinbeck</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1102">
    <d>Marriage is one long conversation, checkered by disputes.</d>
    <a>Robert Louis Stevenson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1103">
    <d>We love in others what we lack in ourselves, and would be everything, but what we are.</d>
    <a>Richard Henry Stoddard</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1104">
    <d>Some pray to marry the man they love, my prayer will somewhat vary; I humbly pray to Heaven above that I love the man I marry.</d>
    <a>Rose Pastor Stokes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1105">
    <d>Each coming together of man and wife, even if they have been mated for many years, should be a fresh adventure; each winning should necessitate a fresh wooing.</d>
    <a>Marie Carmichael Stopes</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1106">
    <d>Why does a woman work ten years to change a man&apos;s habits and then complain that he&apos;s not the man she married?</d>
    <a>Barbra Streisand</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1107">
    <d>In the old days, one married a wife; now one forms a company with a female partner, or moves in to live with a friend. And then one seduces the partner, or defiles the friend.</d>
    <a>J. August Strindberg</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1108">
    <d>Nagging is the repetition of unpalatable truths.</d>
    <a>Edith Summerskill</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1109">
    <d>Try praising your wife, even if it does frighten her at first.</d>
    <a>Billy Sunday</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1110">
    <d>An ideal wife is any woman who has an ideal husband.</d>
    <a>Booth Tarkington</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1111">
    <d>He will hold thee, when his passion shall have spent its novel force, something better than his dog, a little dearer than his horse.</d>
    <a>Alfred Lord Tennyson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1112">
    <d>Nearly all marriages, even happy ones, are mistakes: in the sense that almost certainly (in a more perfect world, or even with a little more care in this very imperfect one) both partners might be found more suitable mates. But the real soul-mate is the one you are actually married to.</d>
    <a>J. R. R. Tolkien</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1113">
    <d>Whether a fellow winds up with a nest egg or a goose egg depends a heap on the kind of chick he married.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1114">
    <d>Marriage is an institution, but who wants to live in an institution?</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1115">
    <d>A good marriage is like a casserole, only those responsible for it really know what goes in it.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1116">
    <d>A marriage is a series of friendships. Love serves as its underlying theme. Friendships provide it with the new challenges around which the relationship further develops. Each type of friendship with ones partner comes into being, rises to a peak of enthusiasm, and then wanes away in our cedar chest of sentimental values. Every once in a while we go to the chest and draw out a friendship item to give us a shot in the arm. Then we put it away till another day.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1117">
    <d>Marriage is like a violin. After the music is over, you still have the strings.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1118">
    <d>Marriage is like a hot bath. Once you get used to it, it&apos;s not so hot.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1119">
    <d>Compromise: An amiable arrangement between husband and wife whereby they agree to let her have her own way.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1120">
    <d>He believes that marriage and a career don&apos;t mix. So after the wedding he plans to quit his job.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1121">
    <d>If it weren&apos;t for marriage, men and women would have to fight with total strangers.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1122">
    <d>Marital Freedom: The liberty that allows a husband to do exactly that which his wife pleases.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1123">
    <d>Marriage is a three ring circus: engagement ring, wedding ring, and suffering.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1124">
    <d>The pretentiously - named ensuite bathroom is a major factor in divorce. Privacy is paramount in marriage.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1125">
    <d>The man who says his wife can&apos;t take a joke forgets that she took him.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1126">
    <d>Marriage isn&apos;t a word... it&apos;s a sentence.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1127">
    <d>One of society&apos;s biggest problems today is that we&apos;ve allowed relationships to be accepted as impermanent, particularly marriage.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1128">
    <d>A little girl at the wedding afterwards asked her mother why the bride changed her mind. What do you mean? responded her mother. Well, she went down the aisle with one man, and came back with another.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1129">
    <d>I dreamed of a wedding of elaborate elegance; a church filled with flowers and friends. I asked him what kind of wedding he wished for; he said one that would make me his wife.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1130">
    <d>It&apos;s not as great a day for the bride as she thinks. She&apos;s not marrying the best man.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1131">
    <d>Every mother generally hopes that her daughter will snag a better husband than she managed to do... but she&apos;s certain that her boy will never get as great a wife as his father did.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1132">
    <d>I told my wife that a husband is like a fine wine; he gets better with age. The next day, she locked me in the cellar.</d>
    <a>Anonymous</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1133">
    <d>Every marriage tends to consist of an aristocrat and a peasant. Of a teacher and a learner.</d>
    <a>John Updike</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1134">
    <d>That a marriage ends is less than ideal; but all things end under heaven, and if temporality is held to be invalidating, then nothing real succeeds.</d>
    <a>John Updike</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1135">
    <d>I&apos;ve been married so long, I am on my third bottle of Tabasco sauce.</d>
    <a>Susan Vass</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1136">
    <d>His purity was too great, his aspiration too high for this poor, miserable world! His great soul is now only enjoying that for which it was worthy!</d>
    <a>Queen Victoria</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1137">
    <d>Marriage is the only adventure open to the cowardly.</d>
    <a>Voltaire (Francois-Marie Arouet)</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1138">
    <d>It&apos;s not the men in my life that counts, it&apos;s the life in my men.</d>
    <a>Mae West</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1139">
    <d>I wonder, among all the tangles of this mortal coil, which one contains tighter knots to undo, and consequently suggests more tugging, and pain, and diversified elements of misery, than the marriage tie.</d>
    <a>Edith Wharton</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1140">
    <d>It is well within the order of thingsThat man should listen when his mate sings;But the true male never yet walkedWho liked to listen when his mate talked.</d>
    <a>Anna Wickham</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1141">
    <d>People who love only once in their lives are shallow people. What they call their loyalty, and their fidelity, I call either the lethargy of custom or their lack of imagination. Faithfulness is to the emotional life what consistency is to the life of the intellect - simply a confession of failures.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1142">
    <d>What a fuss people make about fidelity! Why, even in love it is purely a question for physiology. It has nothing to do with our own will. Young men want to be faithful, and are not; old men want to be faithless, and cannot: that is all one can say.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1143">
    <d>They are horribly tedious when they are good husbands, and abominably conceited when they are not.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1144">
    <d>When a woman marries again it is because she detested her first husband. When a man marries again it is because he adored his first wife. Women try their luck; men risk theirs.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1145">
    <d>On the whole, the great success of marriage in the States is due partly to the fact that no American man is ever idle, and partly to the fact that no American wife is considered responsible for the quality of her husband&apos;s dinners.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1146">
    <d>Long engagements give people the opportunity of finding out each other&apos;s character before marriage, which is never advisable.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1147">
    <d>London is full of women who trust their husbands. One can always recognize them. They look so thoroughly unhappy.</d>
    <a>Oscar Wilde</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1148">
    <d>The best part of married life is the fights. The rests is merely so.</d>
    <a>Thornton Wilder</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1149">
    <d>Marriage is a bribe to make a housekeeper think she&apos;s a householder.</d>
    <a>Thornton Wilder</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1150">
    <d>Our marriage is like anybody&apos;s marriage, It goes through ups and downs. It&apos;s a little garden that you have to tend all the time. When we&apos;re home, it&apos;s not like we walk around all dolled up going, We are celebrities! We are famous! I change diapers. I clean up dog doo.</d>
    <a>Bruce Willis</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1151">
    <d>This would be a much better world if more married couples were as deeply in love as they are in debt.</d>
    <a>Earl Wilson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1152">
    <d>In Hollywood all the marriages are happy, it&apos;s trying to live together afterwards that causes all the problems.</d>
    <a>Shelley Winters</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1153">
    <d>He&apos;s a fool that marries, but he&apos;s a greater that does not marry a fool; what is wit in a wife good for, but to make a man a cuckold?</d>
    <a>William Wycherley</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1154">
    <d>Another of our highly prized virtues is fidelity. We are immensely pleased with ourselves when we are faithful.</d>
    <a>Ida R. Wylie</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1155">
    <d>The secret of a happy marriage remains a secret.</d>
    <a>Henny Youngman</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1156">
    <d>Many marriages would be better if the husband and the wife clearly understood that they are on the same side.</d>
    <a>Zig Ziglar</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1157">
    <d>I&apos;m not a real movie star. I&apos;ve still got the same wife I started out with twenty-eight years ago. </d>
    <a>Will Rogers</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1158">
    <d>I love being married. It&apos;s so great to find that one special person you want to annoy for the rest of your life. </d>
    <a>Rita Rudner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1159">
    <d>A simple enough pleasure, surely, to have breakfast alone with one&apos;s husband, but how seldom married people in the midst of life achieve it. </d>
    <a>Anne Morrow Lindbergh</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1160">
    <d>There is no observation more frequently made by such as employ themselves in surveying the conduct of mankind, than that marriage, though the dictate of nature, and the institution of Providence, is yet very often the cause of misery, and that those who enter into that state can seldom forbear to express their repentance, and their envy of those whom either chance or caution hath withheld from it. </d>
    <a>Samuel Johnson</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1161">
    <d>That is what marriage really means: helping one another to reach the full status of being persons, responsible and autonomous beings who do not run away from life. </d>
    <a>Paul Tournier</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1162">
    <d>Happiness just wasn&apos;t part of the job description back then. You tried to find a helpmate to keep the cold wind and dogs at bay. Happiness just wasn&apos;t part of the equation. Survival was. </d>
    <a>Robin Green</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1163">
    <d>When I meet a man I ask myself, &apos;Is this the man I want my children to spend their weekends with?&apos; </d>
    <a>Rita Rudner</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1164">
    <d>A great marriage is not when the &apos;perfect couple&apos; comes together. It is when an imperfect couple learns to enjoy their differences. </d>
    <a>Dave Meurer</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1165">
    <d>The conception of two people living together for twenty-five years without having a cross word suggests a lack of spirit only to be admired in sheep. </d>
    <a>Alan Patrick Herbert</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1166">
    <d>Man&apos;s best possession is a sympathetic wife. </d>
    <a>Euripides</a>
  </q>
  <q id="1167">
    <d>I used to believe that marriage would diminish me, reduce my options. That you had to be someone less to live with someone else when, of course, you have to be someone more. </d>
    <a>Candice Bergen</a>
  </q>
</root>
